All right, everybody, if you could take
your seats, please. We are starting the
afternoon session on AI systems. We're
going to start with our feature talk
from Junyang, senior director of compute
architecture at NVIDIA on using agents
to build production AI systems, lessons,
pitfalls, and limits.
Make sure it works. Uh sorry.
>> Yeah, thank you. Awesome. Yeah. And
thanks for everyone and uh this is Gian
from Nvidia and I'm glad to be here to
share some of our experience of using AI
agent for our production AI systems. And
uh let me jump into the the main topic
and firstly there's no doubt agent
become a very important and popular
technique and also being a technique it
has its own temper and styles and to
make sure we can use it efficiently we
need to make sure we can leverage
advantage and the disadvantage as well
and also there can be very big
difference between using AI to build
some well showcase compared with
building production usage and for
production scenarios we care a lot about
things like maintainability and
controllability and completeness and It
can be different from building a one-off
demo and this can impose a different
requirement and constraint for us when
we try to use agent
and uh here I will provide some examples
to try to illustrate our experience of
using agent for our production AI system
and there are around three examples
about inference one about training and
for inference we are chooing the 10M and
which is Nvidia powered large model
inference frameworks and this has been
used by a lot of customers and also it
have been used to called a bunch of key
benchmarks submission like Merve and SE
analysis and analysis. So this is indeed
a product grade software and this can
impose additional challenge for us to
use agent and the first example is to
build a agent based bug fixing uh
autobot to make sure we can release our
burden from the daily bug fixing duties
and the workflow is relatively
straightforward. On the left part we
have the agent flow starting from the
bug analysis then do the bug
reproducing. After we we are confident
that the bug is reproducible we will
enter into the bug fixes stated by the
agent. Then the bug the fix will go
through the review phase still by the
agent and after agent feel comfortable
with the code fix we will enter into the
the verification phase still by agent.
After verification done we can mark the
agent fix phase as done. Then we enter
into the human phase and the human here
need to review the code carefully to
make sure the bug fix is not a reward
hacking is not a hacky and it can be
complete enough. And also sometime the
cub need to provide a feedbacks to the
agent workflow to make sure the agent
can continue iteration until it finally
converge.
And here is a dashboard about the back
agent. And on the on the top part we can
see that around the amount the 800 bucks
there around the 33 bugs which already
have the fix from the agent. And if we
zoom in further into the bottom we can
see that among the 313 back fix from
agent. Only 73 of them have been
accepted and landed to our main branch
and there are more than 100 fixes which
can be rejected by human because we feel
the fix is not complete enough or maybe
too reward hacking too superficial is
not great. This indeed is a very current
example indicating the gap between
production requirement and the what
agent can do and this is also the area
we are keeping improving to increase the
ratio of the back fix which can be
finally landed to our main branch
and another example is about using agent
to try to increase our velocity of
supporting new model in tam and there
are new model coming almost every month
sometime every week and we want to make
sure we can support a new model quickly
and so we built a agent based uh
modeling tool to try to increase
velocity. On the left part is a basic
user workflow. We provide a user command
line called a model dash model dash and
bring up and user testing to specify
their model definition their criteria
into the task YML file then can fed into
the agent flow and can run through the
agent process and to make sure human can
do the intervention properly and human
can interrupt the agent execution
process with providing his feedback and
then can retrig the execution to make
sure the agent can be steered towards
the right direction we want. And on the
right part we can have a zoom in work
understanding about the basic agent
flow. This is also a very typical multi-
aent workflow. We have the plan phase.
We have the integation phase. For the
plan phase we have the plan generator.
We also have the plan reviewer. And for
the limited phase we have the coder and
reviewer and QA. And we on purpose try
to divide the responsibility into
several sub aent to make sure each agent
can be very focused. they can use their
content effectively and also they can
share the the common common information
through the admin files they can work
together as a team and here's example
and uh here we are using the gamma for
from Google as example to demonstrate
the effectiveness of the model agent and
in the x-axis is the iteration number
from 0 to 175 and on the y-axis is a
query score and the higher the better
and we can see that starting from the
pler it will trigger execution then the
coder will have a multiteration with the
reviewer. Finally, review sync is okay.
It can pass the board to the QA to do
the evaluation. Then QA can send result
back to the coder. Coder will do it
again again. And there can be intense
interaction between the coder review and
PL and and the QA. Finally, it can be
converged.
And here's another example on top of
that one. And in this in this figure we
just add another uh plan reviewer phase
which we found it very very effective
for us to improve our token efficiency.
And by introducing the additional plan
reviewer we found we can converge with
the same quality with just 35 iterations
we can save our tokens.
And uh next example is also for JAMA for
model and when we finish the model new
model bring up based on agent. We want
to use agent to do performance
improvement. And here we just start from
a low performance baseline with doing
three additional iterations. For the
second and the third iterations we do
have a bunch of optimization finished.
And for the fourth iteration it finally
become converged. So it stopped the
optation process. And for the second and
and third iteration we can notice that
the agent will query some cookbook. The
cookbook consist of the opation
experience accumulated by the team
during the past. We just prepare them in
a structure way. So agent can reuse
them. We can see that in the third in
the second iteration the the agent will
query some cookbook about host
performance operation then apply to the
final operation. In the third iteration
the the agent will create some cook
about ka graph then finally apply to the
organization and also we can notice that
there are bent of operation and have
been done but finally not accepted
because do that the performance again is
very marginal that's decided by a
workflow
and next one is by training and for
training although it has something in
common with the inference also there are
some different characteristics so we are
still using different workflow to
optimize performance for inference and
and training respectively and for
training initially we started from
building a deep agent based a workflow.
Eventually we moved towards building a
very lightweight harness on top of the
general coding agent because we found
the evolution of the general coding
agent actually can take over some
something we have done before based on
agent. So we want to make sure our flow
can be lightweight and adaptive. So we
can leverage the advances of the general
code agent and foundation model. And the
basic architecture of the training proof
agent is very similar like before and
there are some additional thing we added
into the training agent flow such as a
kernel arena in which we try to uh reuse
our history kernels to have to make it
easier for us to generate kernels and
also we have a learning feedback loop in
which the agent can do the truth
analysis about the past execution and
the human can do the review. Then we can
just feed into that inflow to iterate
the tree training agent. Also we have
built a evaluation toolkit which can be
used to evaluate the effectiveness of
inwork flow. So when we add a new skill
and some new sub aent we can be
relatively certain that it will not
introduce too much regressions but it's
actually is not a very ideal. We are
still trying to figure out what is the
best way to defend the agent system
evolution.
And here's example by using the flux
model which is a vision transfer model
to demonstrate the the effectiveness of
the the training profent and this model
actually had a very good performance
baseline based on yeah thank you based
on human observation and starting from
the beginning it has tried more than 120
experiments and some of them will be OM
and some of them can run through but
will be rejected and some will be kept
finally 200 will be kept with the
totally bringing around 20% per
improvement with a very decent number
considering We're using very strong
baseline.
And finally, let me make a conclusion
about some lesson pitfalls and limits we
learned. And firstly, and the the the
nature of agent intelligence is very
different from human intelligence. It's
by nature is a probabilistic based
process. So when we design anything, we
should take that in consideration to
make sure we can use it as advantage and
avoid is a disadvantage. And the the
second the second thing that and when we
are trying to build agent we should make
sure we are not building a very heavy
harness rather we should try to make
sure the customization workflow should
be as lightweight as possible so we can
be able to leverage the the future
evolution of the general coding agent
and foundation model and also there are
some interesting trade-off we should
consider for example and uh and how to
make sure we can balance between the
fully auto agent plus versus the human
plus the agent. Yeah. And uh in on on
the one hand we want to make sure we can
automate everything as much as possible.
On the other hand we found that it's not
rare when we try to combine human plus
agent it can be much more efficient in
term of tok efficiency and iterating
speed. The second thing is that for
production usually we want to centralize
our logic to make sure they can be used
by different places but we we found it's
interest notice due to that agent so
fast. So human plus local custom agent
can can sometimes work more efficiently
than the central centralized agent. So
we should make sure we're aware there
isn't a single single zero bullet. And
the lastly is that we should make sure
we balance between cut agent plus the
the lightweight harness to make sure we
can we can quickly evolve with the new
advantage of the foundation model and
general code agent. Yeah. And with that
I can conclude my sharing. Thank you.
[applause]
And next we have Rick Crawford, uh,
field CTO for Postman, speaking on from
agent demos to production, how Postman
is building reliable AI agentic
infrastructure.
>> Thank you. Uh, again, I appreciate all
of you taking the time to learn about
how we went from prototype to pro
production and delivered an agent that
was that's really driving value with
Impostman. Uh this is a curve that that
some of you out there that are building
agents are probably familiar with. We
went from being an organization that was
very agent first in terms of doing
development, but we recognized that we
wanted to start creating runtime agents
that would make decisions or help us
within the organization. So we started a
prototype and identified different areas
within the business that we might be
able to impact. From that we started
getting some initial excitement whether
it be from our CEO of the board and they
came to us and said hey you know we
really want to move and take some of
these and implement them within our
organization. But then the bigger
challenge comes. All right. Well, how do
I measure this? How do I manage this?
How do I make sure that, you know, we're
delivering something that that we can
maintain? So, this is where things such
as determining ROI and and run books
start coming into play. So, the problem
space that we wanted to address in this
case was enterprise sales. And the
benefit of this is a very uh uh
well-defined process, you know, from
identifying an opportunity to renewing
that deal. There's steps that would go
along in that. And through that there's
a large number of teams that are working
together. The challenges that we're
running into is these teams have a hard
time in terms of handing off that
context of information amongst each
other. And when you look down in terms
of the number of systems that we're
using that pull in, you know, that the
these members and these teams are are
working with, it's uh just a a swarm of
systems, right? And the hard part is is
figuring out well what are the
relationships of data between them.
Ultimately in the end we end up with
this opaque process that where at every
step of the of the way there's some
context that gets lost and so from our
from our uh organization's perspective
we wanted to figure out hey can we
create an agent that can help us through
all fa all the phases of the the sales
process. So uh we did what every you
know engineering organization would do.
We had a hackathon. So we opened this up
to our engineers and over 30 hours they
created a number of agents. But what you
see here is just a swarm of different
systems and connections and agents that
were created. Ultimately, in the end, we
identified, hey, there's this win- loss
agent that's actually able to give us
some really interesting results. And
from this, we we identified three core
problems.
You know, first uh the the the core
problem is that we found that the more
uh discreet the out I mean, sorry, the
more deterministic the outcome, the
better the the agent was. And in case of
the the win loss agent, uh I could get
something such as like, you know, here's
the reasons why we lost this particular
uh account and I could work back from
the reasoning in terms of the results I
got back from the agent say, yeah, you
know, that looks about right. You know,
maybe our price was too high and we we
ended up losing that deal. But if I were
to ask that same agent, all right, well,
what's the best way in terms of
generating leads? It it it kind of went
off the rail. It would start generating
results that were very hard for us to
determine is this right or not? Uh the
other thing we found is like depending
on the complexity of the model the
reasoning that came back was was much
much better but also the confusion in
terms of like understanding those
results became much much harder.
The second thing is this is really a a
compounding problem. Those of you that
have built microservices architecture
are probably recognize this A2A and
agents community agents. What we were
recognizing is that we were ending up
with both compounding cost and
compounding confusion and the challenges
in terms of the handoffs and testing
between these agents became a much
bigger problem.
And then finally uh one of the other
things that that we recognize is that
this is this is a uh decomposition
problem. We what we were were doing is
we were creating individual agents and
what we didn't recognize is that all
these agents were part of the same
domain. Uh if there's any uh design
patterns Martin Fowler fans out there
you probably recognize this pattern as
decomposition. We what we recognized it
was the interface between these systems
and the handoff of context that was the
biggest challenge. So we have these
three problems and what we did is we
came up with a framework of of four
solutions to address it. You know uh at
at the foundation we created a monolith
agent. Uh this agent had an
understanding of all the knowledge and
information that is available as it
related to the sales process. Salesforce
gone calls. It could pull in the
transcripts and I can ask it really
interesting questions and get
interesting results. So you know again
this was a great co-pilot. It was a
great answer uh generator. But the the
challenge we ran into is that you know
if there were some gray areas it would
start making things up. and it was a a
great generalist, but if I started
asking it more specialized questions, it
just it just had too much information.
It wasn't able to give us the right
result. So, we built off of this. The
next stage was the decomposition
component. And there's two key pieces
that we implemented here. One is the
hallucination layer. Don't recommend
something unless you have a clear
understanding of where you're getting
that information from. And if you don't
have it, you need to really explain why
you came up with that result. If if it's
not able to do either of those things,
we would just ignore it. And on top of
it, we wanted to create those domain
specific agents. And this was not a
coding task. These are actually prompts
where I can go in and say, "Hey, you
know, I'm a seller. Here's the things I
would typically do." And it would go out
and it would uh it would start answering
the questions as it related to that
persona. So, it sharpened the output and
it stopped doing a lot of the
hallucinations, but it was confidently
wrong. Uh knowledge and intelligence
does not mean uh strategy. So if I were
to ask a sales agent, what persona
should I sell to? Any guesses out there
in the audience? Which persona would
would typically be responsible for
buying software?
>> Perfect. Yes. Exactly. So would come
back and say, sell to procurement every
time. If I went into my customers and
said, hey, I'm going to sell to your
procurement organization, they'd laugh
us out of the room. So that's where we
started to identify the teams that own
that strategic content and we put them
in charge of adding that information. So
in this case uh the sales team would go
in and add their account plans. the
field engineering organization would add
things such as how you know their
solutions plays and from this we started
to get more and more strategically
relevant information in these agents and
the outputs were becoming more and more
important but the challenge was is at
this point I had this super agent that
had understanding my entire organization
but there were no controls in place and
that's where we implemented this last
layer which is beyond the uh model of of
determining is this right or not or is
this true or not we needed to add
another layer and say, "Hey, is this
content uh related to the job that's
that's requesting it?" So that way, if I
went to the CTO agent, that's not going
to give me all information as it relates
to the P&L of the business. It would it
would take into account my context and
my job role and only give me that
information that was relevant to me. But
what this has done is it identified a
couple of areas that we really wanted to
lean into in terms of developing
additional agents. And really, we've
identified what we call this agent
autonomy curve. And at each steps of
these, it determines like is it the
human or the agent that makes the
decision. There's two decisions that
have to happen. Who's going to request
the information and who determines when
to promote it? At the help piece, the
human is involved in both of those. I
make the qu I I I ask the question, I an
analyze the result. The recommendations
piece, the agent starts doing that. But
where the biggest step change happens is
between that act and own piece where on
the act piece, the agent is doing both
sides of that equation within some
guardrails. And ultimately the own piece
is what we're all developing towards
which is having longunning agents that
will go and own the entire ecosystem.
Now what we saw from this was really
surprising was we started getting
compounding value within our
organization. We went from building an
agent taking a hackathon in 30 hours
down to now we have this framework where
within a matter of hours someone can go
in and create the guardrails and then
build off this body of knowledge that we
have. And on the consumption front, we
went from just having a select audience
of users who are taking advantage of
these agents to now the entire
organization being able to identify how
they too can get value from it. So we
got a a compounding value in terms of
the time it took to develop these agents
and a compounding value in terms of the
people that are getting value of it. And
the core val the the the core benefit of
this too is that we also saw a change of
behavior in our organization as well. So
since the sales people now know that the
context that they create and the
questions that they ask also help the
underlying value of these agents, we're
seeing more discovery go on and we're
seeing better quality of content get
created. Uh I'd be remiss to say that we
also didn't create a platform to help uh
address this issue. We uh we took you
know this this learnings in terms of
creating a platform that um you know we
were able to build these compounding
agents within our organization and we
identified that ultimately in the end I
need to be able to measure the outcomes
that are that are occurring. I need to
be able to have a catalog of these
agents that are available that my teams
could hire fire and understand what the
impact is both in terms of the cost and
the return on the investment. Uh with
that I I appreciate the time today.
Thank you very much and if you have any
questions feel free to just connect with
me on LinkedIn.
>> [applause]
>> Next we have Roel Bakshi, director
applied science edge AI at Amazon
speaking on scale compute to the signal.
Can you hear me?
>> Now,
let's try this. Can you hear me now?
Yeah. All right. So, good afternoon
everyone. My name is Rahu and I lead a
applied science team at Amazon that's
responsible for building our custom
silicon
our latest generation silicon a3 powered
our echo devices that we launched last
fall. So as you can imagine a lot of my
time is spent uh worrying about edge
compute edge devices and edge scale
processing in general and that's going
to be the theme of my talk today.
So, we've spent the last few years uh
talking about how do we get more compute
to our agents and um that that's that's
an important question because it unlocks
new capabilities.
But I want to flip the question today.
What if there wasn't more compute to
give to our agents because of physics
limitations?
And um and and that's going to be one of
the themes of my talk. And the other uh
theme is that a lot of these edge agents
do not require frontier level
intelligence for compute. And we are
able to do some interesting
optimizations
to build use cases in very very defined
power budgets.
All right, let's talk about uh scaling
of compute. How do we give more compute
to our agents? One way to do it is by
spinning up more data centers. We've all
seen uh the new cycles in the last few
years.
Amazon, other hyperscalers, neoclouds,
everyone's building more more and more
gigafactories to give more compute to
our agents. And that's one lever. But on
the other end, there is a real power
ceiling. And I will use variable
technology as uh one extreme of that
ceiling because the constraints are the
hardest there. So if you think about any
variable computer such as a smartwatch,
smart glasses, rings and so on, they
typically have around 1 to one and a
half watt of power to work with. And the
reason is biological. Human skin cannot
tolerate more than 43 43° centigrade of
heat without starting getting burned and
it gets really uncomfortable. So that's
the hard ceiling that we have to work
with on the edge side
and the asymmetry between the edge and
the cloud I think is the fertile ground
for innovation for next generation
hybrid architectures.
Let's look at the second observation.
Um if you agree with this ceiling and if
this is the bounds that we have to work
with there are largely three tiers of
power profiles of what executes on on
the edged scale devices. At the lowest
and most power efficient tier are
processing the signals where they
originate. So think about tiny wakeword
detectors, think about uh event cameras.
you you detect at the source and you
burn minimal energy. At the next level
is what do you want to do with that
signal? If you have to run some
algorithms or if you have to run some
tool calling workflows that requires the
next level of energy still still running
on edge device but notice a few orders
of magnitude more compute more power
that gets burnt. And then finally if uh
if the task requires context that's not
present on the device or if it requires
a world knowledge then you invoke data
center class compute which is even a few
order magnitude more. So what's the
takeaway? The takeaway is escalate only
when the task calls for it.
So the next observation I will share
with you will give you the same
conclusion but with a different couple
of different lenses. So earlier this
year, Berkeley has a function calling
leaderboard which uh which which tracks
the uh function calling efficiency of
different models. And what we saw was
that an a small language model was able
to meet the frontier level compute uh
frontier level uh performance for
function calling task. This task is uh
is it tracks the primitives of function
calling. So the JSON that gets generated
has the right functions, right APIs,
right parameters. But the point is that
for small sets of tasks that are well
defined, we have a pathway of getting
frontier level intelligence on at scale
devices.
And look on the on the right side of the
chart. Um over the last
um decade the cost of transporting one
bit of data across the wireless networks
has gone down many fold. However, what's
not gone down by a similar factor is the
cost of radio. Um so that is both of
these data points are yet another
observation on where the partitioning
should lie. escalation to the next year
is expensive both from an energy um and
battery life perspective and should be
done only when necess necessary.
Um now for what are the opportunities I
think the loop has been well established
for a few um for for more than a decade
if you look at the assistance uh from
Amazon, Apple, Meta, most of them have a
cascaded tier [snorts] where uh you you
detect the wake words and uh keep
the you detect the wake words and keep
escalating only when necessary. What is
missing is a composable runtime and
that's one call to action for this
audience. So let's let's take an example
where you ask your assistant hey what
time's my uh flight is it late now I if
the runtime had the intelligence to know
that for doing this activity I don't
need to turn on any of the perception
sensors cameras microphones all I need
is a turn on the radio and do an API
call then a power budget can be created
and the function calling can take a
certain u dynamic schedule.
Um, so that's on the runtime side. A
couple of other call for actions. U, I
think benchmarks, there's a good
opportunity to enhance those and
Berkeley is a fertile ground for that.
Uh, Berkeley has the function calling
uh, benchmark. I think there's an
opportunity to extend those to also
include jewels per task, not just uh,
number of parameters and accuracy. I
think energy is also an important
frontier. uh we talked about the runtime
and then finally to the silicon
developers in the audience I'd recommend
uh pushing the frontiers lower the
resting power so that we can build more
efficient agents for the edge and that's
a wrap. Thank you so much.
[applause]
We now have John Louu uh principal
product manager at AWS on looping for
model optimization.
All right, good afternoon. Yeah, John
Lou, principal product manager for AWS
Tranium. And uh today we're going to
talk about looping and model
optimization on AWS Tranium, which is
the custom AI accelerator used by
leading frontier labs such as Anthropic
and OpenAI.
So why is this relevant now? And when
you think of it from there's probably
two angles, right? First from the
business angle. As Peter Dantis
mentioned yesterday's keynote, the
future of Agentic workloads is going to
be one with many chips customuilt for
the different purposes of that Agentic
workload. Now, at the same time, Agentic
harnesses, Agentic solutions, they've
been gaining adoption. They've been
getting more mature. As you'll see, the
model optimization path on custom
hardware is actually very well suited
for this type of workload
there.
So what does a typical model
optimization loop look like? Well, you
start by creating a functional model on
the custom hardware and then you take
some knobs on the model level and kind
of uh hardness level type of
configurations such as changing the
parallelisms, changing the sequence
lengths, batch sizes and then you
profile that, right? You profile and see
how the performance is and based on that
you go through a loop. you change more
things at a certain level, you're going
to maximize what you can get from these
outof-box knobs. So then you drop into
the kernel development and think of
kernels just as custom functions that
let you unlock more performance on
hardware. Again, you tune those, you
profile it, and you you have that second
loop. But you're not done yet. Once that
kernel is optimized, you actually need
to do end-to-end model evaluation as
well, just to make sure it works. And
now you complete yet another loop. So
you can see this is actually a
multi-layer multivariable type of
optimization problem. Very well suited
for looping.
And we've actually released some open
source agents and skills to help our
customers turn what took weeks into
pretty much ours. These skills help
people create functional models on AWS
Trainium author kernels, profile
kernels, and now we're working on the
optimization loop as well.
So let's dive a little deep into one of
these optimization loops which is the
kernel optimization loop. And this is a
common setup, right? We use what's
called an a planner and executive type
of model. And the goal that we try to
loop towards is what's the gap towards
the maximum u performance that that
hardware can achieve on your particular
model. So starting from step zero,
there's another loop that identifies for
a given inference workload, what's the
best settings and it passes that to our
planner agent. That's step one. The
planner agent looks at this and it
measures the gap to roof line and it
looks at its local local knowledge base
and identifies the best optimization
campaigns. It passes that to the
executive agents which runs these
campaigns and then based on those
outcomes, it records the outcomes in the
knowledge base. Did this kernel work?
Did it fail? what were the constraints
and then we measure the performance of
that end toend model and finally based
on those outcomes we decide to promote
or reject that kernel and of course
update the knowledge base as well and
that completes the loop.
So I want to share some insights that we
have from building these loops and
hopefully they're applying to you know
not just the specialized domains but
everyone's loops and number one a
recurrent theme that you've heard from
is agents are very sophisticated in
coming up with cheating right the
standard approach of telling agents
agents don't cheat that's not enough the
mitigations of creating held out data
sets and making sure that agents aren't
memorizing things that's the baseline
what you need to think about is every
single part of your agentic workload is
going to be manipulated by that agent
especially the area where you're
measuring performance.
The second insight which is whenever
your agent fails don't go through and
just start fixing that agent itself.
Check the visibility scope. Right? In
one of our examples that agent was
actually maximizing local memory usage
for the kernel which is the right
decision but it affected all the shared
memory usage for the other kernels that
were running on the model.
So check your visibility scope as you're
designing your agent actions.
Third, when you're creating these
knowledge bases and whenever something
goes wrong, check to see if one of your
existing rules caused the error. Edit
and delete that rule instead of just
adding yet another rule because now
you're going to start confusing the
agent with more rules.
And on a related topic, that knowledge
base that you have has a shelf life,
right? In specialized domains, this
knowledge base is very helpful to get
your agent started. But as the model's
general training catches up, now you're
going to have some kind of conflict.
Your agent's going to get confused.
Should I use the knowledge base or
should I use the model training? So, a
good practice is to constantly remove
the knowledge base and check the
performance of your agent. And if it
improves, it's time to prune that
knowledge base.
Finally, in specialized domain, there's
no standard data set or benchmark for
success. So, as you're designing your
process for improving things, you're
also defining what that better thing is.
And you have to design the benchmark and
evaluation as a first class design
component before you get to the rest of
your loop because it affects how that
loop operates.
So, you know, a very short amount of
time. If you want to learn more, check
out our blog, check out our GitHub, and
thank you very much for your time.
[applause]
We now welcome Jang R Kim, head of AI
systems infra skinex on disagregated LLM
serving with shared memory KV cache at
Rexcale.
Okay. Hello everyone. My name is Junior
Kim as from SKH Highix as I'm senior
director and I also working for the SRC
as a cell.
So today I want to talk about the new
memory as a disegregated physically
disagregated pool memory. So this is a
memory pool disagregated with from the
servers. So in this diagram so node main
server and this is a memory pool box is
a really disagregated memory pool. So
multiple server can use this memory pool
at the same time with the two mode. The
first one is a memory pooling. So each
node can dynamically allocated the
additional memory but that memory region
is isolated between node but is a
sharing mode. Sharing mode is a multiple
node can share can see the same memory
address space. So each node can access
the same data. So uh we are very
interested in this this sharing feature.
So we quickly uh integrated this memory
pool with the realm serving system. So
we successfully deployed this system and
we demonstrated at the last year so many
event. So uh in this diagram so there
are four servers and four server can uh
can work with the so many uh random
serving component and the middle of
middle of a server middle of a rack that
is a niagara that is a real physical as
a pool memory
uh in this scenario in this uh demo
scenario so uh there is a we use that
memory pool for transferring the key
value cache the at first the prepare
After prepare we need to deliver the key
cache to the decoding side. So by using
the two memory copy uh store and load we
can deliver the key cache to the
decoding so decoding node but uh is in
we can find that in this system the old
key cache can be stored in the memory
pool. So we can reuse it for the next
request without any some additional
storing operation for reusing.
So as a result we can improve the system
performance compared with the uh all
recmp computation. This is nxl and nm
cache is in server DM based cable cash
stoing. But uh important part is why we
can have this kind of benefit. The first
one is a faster uh fast interer is a
data movement by using the pulled
memory. Yeah instead of using the TCP IP
we generally use RDMA. This is a fast
but this pulled the memory based data
sharing is a faster than RDMA. So we can
have a performance improvement for the
RM serving system. Second one is by
using the pool memory based data uh
sharing. So we can have some another
benefit we can relate the GPU HPM
immediately by operating the key cache
to the pool memory. So if there is a
okay it's if there is out of memory at
the decoding side and prepare side but
we can continuously do the prepare
because we already uploaded that keeper
cache to the pool memory side and as to
store the keeper cache and for reuse the
cuber cache there are many contention
can be happened in the GPU side GPU side
the PCI bandwidth and network side the
PCI bandwidth there are many contention
but by using the our pool memory based
data sharing transports we can remove
this kind of additional uh contention.
So we deployed as in the agent AI
serving system. So we should reuse the
many amount of large amount of key
cache. So we applied this system uh we
applied the agentic AI serving system uh
to the pool memory environment and we
can find this kind of performance
improvement compared with the moonake
and cache. that is a very initial
performance number but uh by end of this
year I'm working with the many uh
collaboration parties 25 around the 25
parties so we are preparing the five
more system PC such as multimord serving
and run-term memory management and so we
are trying to build the rear system with
the pool memory uh for the HPC US-based
national uh system so yeah let's see so
how how the pool memory can change the
AI system. That's it. Thank you.
>> And now welcome Ben, senior director uh
core ML at Together AI and unified
orchestration system for verifier free
evolution.
>> Thank you.
So today I'll be talking about u squeeze
evolve um our approach for unified
multimodel orchestration system for
verifier free evolution with
applications for uh scientific
discovery.
So let's take a look at the um
components for scientific discovery. Um
this one is taken from taken from sky
discover. So um there are four distinct
components. Uh the first one is context
builder. Um the context builder's goal
is to uh provide uh problem context as
well as um injecting ideas uh guidance
uh reflections of uh previous mistakes
and success into the prompt. And the
prompt is given to a solution generator
in this case LLM where it has access to
environments um such as execution or
ability to um uh uh look up the web um
and uh solutions are passed to um
evaluator where evaluator's goal is to
um um provide scores, provide logs,
provide uh feedback or um uh necessary
artifacts. And these solutions and
metadata are passed to uh solution
selector which uh selects uh sample
solutions to be passed to context
builder so that we can um use it um in
in the next loop.
Uh prior methods for uh um uh discovery
frameworks uh often require external v
uh ver evaluator. So um in the domain of
uh physical science for example
evaluators can be costly and uh
timeconuming. So um our goal is to um to
answer the question of um what would be
the upper bound of um uh evolution
system without uh uh verification in the
loop and can we also reduce cost.
Uh one of the problems for um
um one of the problems for evolution
system is uh degradation of um
solutions. Um long story short, if we
use a single model to perform uh
evolution is often the case um degrading
the performance because there's so only
so much uh entropy and only so much
creativeness in in uh a single model. So
our solution is to use uh multiple
models uh to tackle this diversity uh
problem. So uh in this case um multiple
solutions or multiple generations are
selected from previous generations and
current uh generations and assign
probability fitness scores. In this
case, we use uh log token uh sorry uh
token lock probabilities or um
diversities of solutions as a uh fitness
function. And uh in order to increase uh
diversity
um we pass the uh difficult solutions to
um expensive models um similar to um uh
single model uh framework. Whereas if we
uh identify the solutions as being um uh
easy enough to evaluate and combine, we
pass them to a cheaper model. And in
this case, we are able to increase
diversity and also um increase cost
effectiveness. So uh the result here
the result here shows that um um for the
full pipeline with uh 10 uh evolution
steps with Gemini uh 3.1 Pro um the
accuracy on ARC AGI is uh 97.5 this is
with uh 10 steps and cost is around uh
$7 per task. But um in the scenario
where we use uh a cheap model in the mix
which is the Gemini 3.0 zero flash.
We're able to retain the same accuracy
with only uh two steps uh two evolution
steps while uh achieve um cost savings.
Uh the uh dollar per task is around um
$5 uh.9.
Another interesting observation is that
uh in the um vision based uh task uh not
you not having to use the vision
component uh for the aggregator stage
also allow us to um increase the cost
effectiveness uh significantly. For
example, in the red curve here where we
use a a strong uh multimodel model, uh
the performance um gets quite high, but
also notice that the cumulative dollar
per problem is also um proportionally
high. But in the squeeze evolve uh
method where we use a combination of um
powerful model as well as uh cheaper
tier model we're able to reduce the cost
significantly and in some case inter in
the heterogeneous case uh we're able to
outperform the single model scenario. So
we're uh very excited to share this and
this work has been integrated uh into
Nvidia Dynamo. Uh huge shout out to
Nvidia and also we have cloud code
plug-in available. Um yeah, thank you so
much.
[applause]
Now we have Duchar Krishna, associate
professor Georgia Tech and CEO of Infana
on how agentic AI is rewriting the rules
of AI infrastructure.
>> Thank you. Um I guess I'm audible. So uh
so we're at 1:45. I know it's officially
the end of this session time and my
superpower as a professor is I can rush
through any number of slides in 5
minutes but I'll you know try to keep
this short and uh talk you through about
uh you know how agentic AI is rewriting
the rules of AI infrastructure. Uh so
we've entered you know a new era of
what's called tokconomics right where we
essentially feed in AI workflows to our
AI systems and outcomes tokens. And
essentially, you know, there's a lot of
metrics we've started caring about
things like tokens per second, tokens
per watt, tokens per dollar. Now, in
this ecosystem where you have a workflow
on one end and hardware on the other,
the software stack that's really, you
know, in the middle becomes very, very
crucial to get token efficiency. Now, a
lot of the inference serving stacks that
are out there today were really built,
you know, for the chatbot era, right? So
essentially you know their
characteristics are they can run you
know typically one model at a time
really optimized for static execution
paths uh each request is assumed to be
independent you know a lot of kernel
optimizations and the hardware is
primarily homogeneous right for the most
part GPUs now of course we are at the
agentic AI uh you know summit so the
question is you know what changes with
uh with agents so there's two core
things that we are we observe as you
know uh emerging trends that are
inevitable so the first is around you
you know dynamism right so uh we've
already heard a lot of talks there's a
lot of models there's tool calls dynamic
fluctuating demands interdependent tasks
and a lot of workflow level
optimizations
and the second key trend in fact
speakers below before me also did a
great job talking about this there's
heavy hetrogenity so there's already you
know uh big use of CPUs for handling you
know anything that's not uh an LLM in
addition there's a lot of other hardware
out there that is really specialized and
optimized for different parts of the
task And what's also interesting is in
this agentic era, this is again you know
a data point I got from uh you know just
uh a talk yesterday from Google there's
10 to 100x more uh you know computations
you know compared to a non-agentic
workflow. So, so again the software
stack becomes even more important,
right? So, so it's important for us to
now like really try to understand what's
going on behind the scenes, right? So,
if you try to demystify all of this
fundamentally, if you go down all the
way from the workload to the the model
layer to the software to the hardware,
there are essentially, you know, choices
across the stack, right? There are like
tons and tons of choices and
optimization opportunities throughout
the stack. And if I kind of abstract
these out, you know, ultimately what we
are trying to do is get, you know,
end-to-end service level objectives
which could be related to whatever the
agent, you know, cares about for that
application. And on the other end, we
care about a lot of infrale objectives,
right, for uh for running our data
centers efficiently. And so now you have
this, you know, cross-d dependent space,
trillions of choices, diverse SLOs's and
rapidly evolving components within the
stack, right? which means that you know
it's kind of almost inevitable that you
know you would go wrong when you pick
something and the chances of going wrong
are actually very high and the cost of
going wrong is even higher. So then the
question is how do you extract token
efficiency in this you know very very
complex ecosystem right so so there's a
famous quote right you can't optimize
what you cannot measure so over the past
many years we've been you know working
closely with like academia industry uh
partnerships to really understand the
end toend stack for AI systems right all
the way from the hardware to the
software uh to to like all the way to
the workloads right and uh we've also
worked very closely with a lot of uh
benchmarking and standardization agency
to create APIs with which a lot of these
benchmarks and tools can work
interchangeably and this has led to
massive adoption. So I'll especially
call out uh Chakra which is an
initiative we started with ML Commons.
We just released Chakra a few weeks ago
at MLS. So this is basically a
benchmarking methodology for distributed
AI platforms uh and Astrasim which is a
simulation platform for studying
distributed AI networks. And with this
adoption, what's also interesting is,
you know, throughout uh, you know, uh, a
lot of the companies that we've been
working with, you know, from
hyperscalers to hardware vendors to OEMs
to test vendors, one thing that keeps
coming out is that the only way to get
efficiency is, you know, optimizing
across the stack like optimizing just
parts of the stack will not work. So
that gets me to, you know, something I'm
personally very excited about. So, uh,
we just started Infraana. Uh this is a
company that's built uh and automated,
you know, agent plus hardware aware full
stack optimizer and we're already seeing
you know massive speed ups over the
state-of-the-art inference frameworks
out there and you know you'll hear a lot
more from us as we as we come out of
stealth. Uh so you know if you you can
feel free to find me anytime at the
conference or you know email me if you
want more if you have any questions and
I'm happy to you know uh kind of
officially call this session to a close.
Thank you.
[applause]
All right, that wraps up our AI systems
section. We are now on to enterprise AI
where the first speaker would be Anna
Reus. He is co-founder CTO of Factory AI
building software, excuse me, building
the software factory.
Yeah.
>> Hey everybody. Um excited to chat today
about um is it this thing? Oh yeah.
Great. Excited to chat today about this
concept of the software factory. Uh and
a little bit about what we're doing. Uh
and so when I talk about the software
factory, I always like to reflect on how
uh insanely quick this entire field has
actually evolved, right? Three and a
half years ago basically. Uh we started
three and a half years ago and back then
uh you know autocomplete was basically
the only sort of like known workflow for
introducing um AI into the uh at least
like dev tools that were um let's just
say like like what we now consider to be
standard like agentic or semi-agentic
LLM based workflows. Um and so
autocomplete moved on to chat bots, chat
bots moved on to agents and agents are
now moving into uh software factories.
So what does that actually mean? Well,
uh if the slides were ordered well and I
that I had sent my bad uh I would be
talking about uh exactly this which is
that a software factory is really um
this process where signals flow in uh
into your uh into sort of your system
right or your business. These signals
could take a lot of different forms, but
traditionally if you're building like
let's say like a uh piece of software
that helps people like manage uh
information or you're bu you're like a
school system and you're you're trying
to build some software for that. Maybe
you're a financial services firm and
you're doing a bunch of stuff to manage
transactions. The signals that you're
ingesting might be things like customer
feedback, internal data telemetry, um an
executive saying we're going to pivot,
right? Like it could be a lot of
different things. And all of these
signals today, human beings actually
triage themselves in their heads and
it's almost never explicitly represented
in any like real system. Uh at that
point, uh those signals are then sort of
ingested and luckily if you're like
operating on signals for things like a
bug or an error, you hopefully have
telemetry for that. Um but ultimately
that triage process is very human-driven
today in almost all organizations. Then
you go and you start to plan. And really
that's the first time that you start to
encode any of this information anywhere.
You'll typically do this in something
like Jira or maybe notion. Maybe you'll
do you're doing it in Confluence. But
either way this planning process tends
to be fairly unstructured at most
organizations. And then you start to
move into actually writing the code,
validating the code, shipping, deploying
and ultimately with deployed monitored
software it starts to generate more
signals. So what's interesting is this
implicit feedback loop exists at almost
every company building software and yet
an explicit model of this does not
really exist anywhere. Um and so what
we've sort of found is that what's
interesting about this is that if you
think about the hard part of this
problem, uh coding is just not the hard
part. It's basically in fact the easiest
part of this problem. Uh and in fact all
of the other things around actually
writing code are the hard part, the part
that leads to mess. And and I think that
when a lot of people think about sort of
the velocity aspect of you know you have
an AI CEO or saying like oh AGI's here
it's like six months away you're going
to see 100x productivity and then you
yourself have not seen that at your
company. A lot of people are sort of
asking the question why is that? Well,
really it's because you're actually only
AI like one narrow slice of this process
and then a lot of it remains a very
human-driven synchronous workflow where
you go and you say to a machine
something that basically looks like
autocomplete. I want the thing, you give
it back to me. I send you on a task, it
comes back to me, right? And so what
what we want to do is we want to say um
how do we basically design a system that
allows signals to flow all the way to
deployed software without human
intervention right and so when I say
without human intervention I don't mean
uh without humans at all being involved
in the process right and that sort of
leads to a lot of the questions that I
think people are asking right now which
are probably very hard to read on this
slide uh and like things like how do we
prevent cost overruns if this fully
autonomous system is operating you you
know sort of like without impunity. Um,
how do we ensure we have access to the
best possible AI systems? Uh, regardless
of like who wins the model race, who
wins sort of the AI layer race, right?
You've already heard, I think that last
one did a good job of showing how much
complexity there is in the vendor
ecosystem, right? You don't really want
to be making a bet on any one of these
things. You just want to be building a
system. So, how do you do that? Right?
Also, how does the role of the human
evolve in this new system? um you know
if you're not uh intervening as the
signal flows all the way to deployed
software what are you doing right well I
think that and and you know and then how
does that change the organization I
think that generally you should then be
thinking well okay if I'm not doing that
then I'm clearly somehow involved in
building this system or maintaining
refining or evolving the software
factory and that is ultimately the new
role for people um and so if you're
thinking about what does it mean for me
to build refine or evolve a software
factory factory, you should be thinking
about a couple things of like one, how
should this system be designed? Well, we
have a couple of opinions. The first is
that you should be model independent,
right? Like if you are operating in a
world where you're going to delegate
your software factory to a single model
vendor and they're going to make a ton
of arguments that are actually not that
compelling, but maybe they'll make
compelling arguments that, oh, you have
to verticalize aggressively and your
agent harness needs to be with the
model. We found like empirically that's
like very clearly not true. you actually
want to aggregate and commoditize that
model layer in order for you to have
access to the true PTO frontier of both
cost and quality. All right. And so then
the second thing is who should own this?
Well, uh, you know, we literally make
SAS to help you build this, but I still
think that you should be in control of
whatever software you use, right? And so
we also offer things like on-prem,
airgapped, all the way to basically, you
know, you sign a contract and we throw
it over and we, you know, we don't see
it again. And that is because we believe
you should be the sovereign of your
software factory. It's incredibly
important that your software factory
operates regardless of what vendors come
and go because ultimately your software
factory is your company, right? If you
build software, you're you're basically
describing the new version of your
business. And so it's really important
that you're able to maintain and control
that. Um, and then the last is you
should really be thinking about your
software factory as something that
operates across every action that takes
place inside of your product and
engineering organization. So if there's
basically any activity, any context, any
workflow, that's a part of your software
factory. Um, and there's a lot of stuff
that you can do, right? Everything from
code review to security analysis to
testing, documentation, right?
[clears throat]
Incident response. But at the end of the
day, uh, each of these workflows should
probably operate with effectively a, um,
shared agent core because I think that
there was actually I I really enjoyed
the the talk just a bit ago that was
talking about this idea of if you have
like a ton of different specialized
agents like a code review agent and a
incident response agent, you sort of end
up in this weird microser system where
you're hyper optimizing each of those
agent architectures for what is
ultimately one sort of shared workflow,
which is gathering information acting on
information on computer systems uh and
informing the user as it does that,
right? And so you really sort of want
this singular AI agent system where the
context and the workflow changes, right?
Code review is obviously a very
different workflow from incident
response, but ultimately it's actually
at a high level all just going to be
like computer control on top of the
agent with context. So using a shared
agent core to then operate across many
surfaces that your software factory may
touch is also super important, right? Um
and at in a larger organization, you're
probably thinking about things like
governance. How do we handle uh you know
consistency? How do we handle uh
ensuring that you know an agent doesn't
go and like drop a bunch of tables,
right? What about IT ops? Um a bunch of
stuff like this sort of uh becomes very
clear. I would argue that this is
ultimately the responsibility of
whatever agent platform you're using to
enforce all of these standardized
controls and you really should be asking
what are like is there a page called
like enterprise controls or
organizational controls and how many are
there right and if you're not seeing
hundreds of different scenarios that a
agent platform has gone through in order
to basically refine preventing bad
things from happening with agents then I
would just start looking out and see
like what is out there there's open
source standards docker just came out
with a really interesting sort of like
35 five control system for this where
they said what are the agent controls
that you need inside of an agent
platform sort of vendor neutral. I
thought that that was like a pretty cool
way of uh delivering that. Um and so
then that sort of leads you to this next
interesting point which is that almost
certainly after all this work of talking
about agents you've actually maybe not
fixed the biggest problem that's
preventing agents from succeeding which
is the state of your environment. Uh,
and so I I always like draw the analogy
of human beings. We don't like when we
were 200,000 years ago. We're like not
that different. We're pretty much the
same humans more or less, but we're so
much more advanced. What happened? Well,
we completely changed our environment
around us, right? And so, yes, you can
wait for agents to continue to get
better. They will probably continue to
get better. Uh, but I think that really
updating the codebase and the
engineering system around your software
factory is by far the highest leverage
changes that you can make. And really
that's looking at things like uh dev
reproducibility, environment
cleanliness, linting, type checking,
quality tests. Really the actual sort of
tidbit would be what is the amount of or
like do you have enough deterministic
verifiable feedback loops inside of your
organization to give agents the ability
to succeed without needing to consult a
human. Right? So it's one thing if you
wait for code review to say that code is
not organized well. It's much better to
have a deterministic signal that says
that code is not organized well, right?
And agents can then use that to loop and
validate their work until they succeed.
Um, so yeah, here's a laundry list of
control uh controls that matter, right?
Security, governance, and enablement.
All of these are super important. I
don't want to like blaze through this,
but I think it's like the type of thing
where you can take a photo. Ultimately,
my view is that uh your agents are going
to have to have access ultimately in the
software factory. That is dangerous.
It's just how it's going to happen. Like
it's not really a matter of if, but just
when. And so you have to treat them the
way that you would human beings, which
is you build out systems of control and
you build out layers, right? So how do
you prevent a human from dropping an
important table in your company? Well,
you may be relying today on basically
telling them not to do that, right? That
is actually not good. And probably the
analogy that if you've ever uh thought
about building so like sort of software
organizations for more than say 50 to 75
people, you start to realize that even
50 to 75 incredibly competent people,
someone's going to eventually drop the
database, right? And so you really have
to think about introducing these agents
as sort of scaling up the uh guard
rails, prevention, etc. towards what an
organization maybe 10 times larger than
your current organization would look
like. which is sort of interesting
because if you're a fivep person
startup, that means you're actually
operating at the what the controls that
maybe a 50 person company would need. If
you're a 50 person company, 500 people,
right? And so you really have to uplevel
a lot of the guard rails and the systems
that are actually very well established
and and I think you you don't really
need to reinvent the wheel here. You
should look at software development best
practices and then just ensure that
they're being enforced on those agents.
Um, and so on that idea, I think that
this is like probably the most
interesting and evolving part of humans
roles in the software factory. I sort of
alluded to this earlier, but we've
already just labeled a bunch of things
that I'm suggesting that you change.
Right? This is what we're going to do.
We're going to say, what are the
guardrails that exist? Oh, there aren't
guardrails for that. Let's actually
implement the guardrails for that. We're
going to look at where agents are
failing, and what are we going to do?
We're going to add context. We're going
to update the workflows that the agents
are following. Um, a lot of actually
like if you've listened to any talks and
I highly recommend listening to a talk
about like chip fabricators or any of
these really advanced like industry 4.0
actual real life factories, you start to
realize there's like whole dedicated
roles of process control, process
management, loop management of people
who basically just look and say, "Okay,
great. Like we lost 10% of the the
resources due to this bad inefficiency.
Let's go fix that part of the factory."
And then we're going to reiterate and
sort of refine. We're basically going to
be doing that for software systems. And
so I think a lot about this process of
how do you observe failures in your
software factory? How do you intervene
when you are seeing either one like a
one-off or two a consistent failure? Uh
and three how do you then refine
iteratively those workflows? It ends up
kind of as everything does boiling down
to evaluate
whether or not a failure happened. Um
the case study here would be code
reveal. Like pretty much everyone in
here who's thinking about a software
factory, you can the first
[clears throat] step you can make is
building a system that makes you
confident to merge maybe five, then 10,
then 50, then 100% of your PRs without
human code review. What would that look
like? What is that system? And that
doesn't mean that you still don't need
humans to understand the code changes.
That's sort of a separate part. But
ultimately, you probably need something
like what self-driving cars had, which
was kind, this is kind of dark, but like
fatalities on the road. Like everyone
knows when the fatalities on the road
drops below and you know the order of
magnitude is kind of what's interesting.
Maybe it's the same as humans. Maybe
it's 10 times less than humans but
there's some sort of metric where we go
great we think this is safer than the
humans. So we're happy to let this thing
start driving. Similarly with validation
you need to get to the point where you
say what is my what are my metrics that
I'm going to measure to allow that
review step to happen without a human in
the loop. And maybe you feel that it's
like bugs, maybe it's incident
responses, uh, or sorry, incidents,
maybe it's MTR, maybe you want to look
at a bunch of these things together and
say, "We think that maybe our system is
now safer than humans being involved, so
we're going to let that thing run." Um,
and you should probably have engineers
thinking about that inside your company.
Um, I sort of just alluded to this as
well, which is what are the outcomes
then you're measuring. I would be
looking at cycle time. I'd be looking at
code shelf life, incident time, number
of bugs that have occurred. Do not
measure tokens. it's really does not uh
give you a ton of information or value.
Um and so you can also though look at
costs in other ways maybe just like cost
per code change cost per like loop or
per week right almost treating it in a
way that we do humans with salary. Uh
and those are the things that you can
then measure and iterate and optimize
against. So if you take three things
away it would be one invest in agent
readiness that is super important. We
build a product for that which is pretty
cool. Um two govern before you scale.
you want to implement all this stuff
before you start immediately rolling
this out across the whole company. And
three, you got to be thinking about the
outcomes that you want to measure in
advance because uh I think the last deck
just had this uh you can't optimize
against something that you aren't
measuring. So really important to have
all this stuff together. Uh and
hopefully this was helpful in thinking
about building your software factories.
Thank you.
We now welcome Anka Goyle, a principal
software uh staff software engineer at
LinkedIn on infrastructure for
longunning agents.
>> Um good afternoon everyone. Uh I'm
Ankit. I'm a principal staff engineer at
LinkedIn in the AI platforms team. uh
I'm going to give an overview of our
agentic platform and uh talk about some
of the trends we are observing as we
scale agent-driven experimentation.
So first I'd like to introduce some of
the agents that we are running in
production and that have delivered
significant business value. So first is
model generation. So LinkedIn runs 400
plus models in production that are
written in TensorFlow and we are trying
to migrate them to PyTorch. Now we have
written an agentic workflow that can do
that and the challenging part in this
agent is ensuring that the new models
that we are generating they perform
either on par or better than the
production deployed models and those
production deployed models usually have
been like human tuned by engineers over
like you know multiple months or even
years. The next is performance
optimization agent. So this is an agent
that we run in our cluster that looks
for low utilization jobs. it it
basically you know profiles them,
benchmarks them uh we have a whole
knowledge base that our team has
collected over the years uh and it
optimizes them and like creates ser
requests for different teams to review
and then finally to build on top of that
we have an autonomous research agent
where engineers can define an objective
and this agent will autonomously do
architectural sweeps or hyperparameter
tunings uh to to basically you know
optimize for the objective.
Now all these agents sort of have a
fundamental life cycle that they share.
Uh the first one is you know an engineer
writes a hypothesis uh writes an
objective uh and the agent then forms an
hypothesis. It uh generates the code
runs it on our GPUs and then the agent
evaluates the outcome. Now this loop can
run over hours or even days uh
continuously autonomously uh without
human intervention.
Now with int with like introduction of
agents into the infrastructure we
observe like certain shifts in how uh
you know we how to architecture the
infrastructure. One is the UX uh
traditionally we focused a lot on rich
on creating rich abstractions so that
you know engineers can write their
machine learning pipelines or their
training loops easily or how to access
data those are still important but th
that code today is now generated by LLM.
So uh the focus of our users have sort
of shifted towards creating agentic
workflows and creating appropriate
guardrail so that agents don't deviate
from from the original task. The other
is compute. Uh engineers typically
launched you know a limited number of
longunning jobs in our cluster. Uh
couple of minutes of delay was usually
amortized you know over the run of the
uh training job. Agents however can
launch hundreds of job within a very
short period of time uh and ranging from
like few minutes to hours to even days.
And finally the trust uh we we kind of
inherently trust the code written by
humans or engineers. Uh however agent
generated code needs to run in a very
[snorts] constrained environment.
So to support this in our infrastructure
agent is just like any other task. uh
users write agents as if they're writing
any other like PyTorch or TensorFlow
job. Uh the difference is the agent code
is untrusted. So it it runs in a highly
restricted environment like no egress,
no access to credentials and all the
communication goes to via our proxies
using the agents on identity. Now
natural language prompts they tend to
not do well when uh agents are running
for long periods of time. So we follow
harnesses code approach for all our
agents. uh each stage is defined in code
and has its own responsibilities and
additionally and more importantly the
scorer and uh evaluators are also
defined in code uh so that agents don't
do reward hacking or they don't diverge
from the path and then we have a whole
ecosystem of tasks memory management on
how do agents share their learnings with
other agents of the same type different
type and then the notifications for
human in the loop type of interactions.
Now given these agents can run over long
periods of time, we also have a uh
robust checkpointing and restore uh so
that agents can autonomously recover
from any failures without any human
interventions.
Now as I mentioned these agents can
launch a very large number of jobs and
this creates sort of a bottleneck in our
control plane which has been sort of
designed with lot of abstraction and
those abstractions add up once agents
start launching like lot of jobs. So
we've built a customized control plane
with which maintains like a warm pool of
GPU pods and it can provide a very low
latency job launch. Similarly the since
we are running agent generated code this
this uh pool of pods are is like highly
restricted with like no egress read only
access to data and like uh it runs in a
highly unprivileged mode.
So the impact of agents is clear. uh the
number of experiments in our cluster has
grown by 100% over the last 6 months. We
are continuously investing uh in our
evaluations so that uh our experiments
can turn to real production value.
Additionally, we are investing in SLMs
for specialized tasks and we're also
looking uh into GPU sharing techniques
so that we can get more utilization out
of our GPUs as they keep getting bigger
but not all the tasks are bigger to
utilize the full GPU.
So the goal with agents for us is to
take more shots at the goal. The more
shots at the goal we take, the more
improvements we can make to our models
and eventually, you know, improving the
member experience and the and providing
more business value. So thank you.
[applause]
And now we have Daniel Humla for lead AI
engineer at BMW research on multi-agent
patterns and reliable orchestration.
>> Hi everybody, I'm Daniel Homola from BMW
research. Uh the title sounds like a
patterns talk but the core question is
simple. Uh in an agentic system or a
multi- aent system, the core question is
uh who should handle this piece of work?
Reliable orchestration depends on making
that choice well repeatedly at runtime.
Uh this is my background. Recently I'm
working on agent architecture basically
system level architecture for agentic AI
customer products and a graphical user
interface agents basically computer use
agents that operate screens like users
do. And for the motivation behind the GU
agent paradigm you can have a look on
this talk that I held last year at AI
engineer conference. If you're
interested why an enterprise would
consider this technology as a one of the
agents, uh let me ground my talk in the
multi-agent incar voice assistant where
we could have three agents. Uh you might
have navigation agents for finding your
route, car control agents for
manipulating your windows, uh seats,
climate and also this uh for example GU
agent, computer use agent that can
operate for example applications through
the screen. uh above them then you have
the orchestrator who acts coordinates
the execution and sometimes combines the
results and uh after all the hard part
in the orchestration is not the patterns
and how do we uh put stuff between the
agents it's about the delegation choices
and the coordination making it reliably
under constantly changing context and
there are many coordination patterns uh
but they all come down to the delegation
decision to the runtime decision in a
handoff the control transfers to another
agent. In agents as tools, the
orchestrator delegates work to the
specialized agents and waits for the
result. In uh uh rooting, the classifier
or the rooter dispatches the each turn
to the specialist. But there are other
patterns. Every enterprise defines their
patterns in a different naming, but
essentially it's the same. It's about
the choice. It's about the delegation
that we need to do and it's about the
which agent or tool should we uh
delegate this piece of work to and it
can all sound like ordinary tool
selection but it isn't. Tool selection
is often evaluated in uh against one
ground label but for agent delegation
who should handle this work in this
context it's different. The overlap is
normal there because we have multiple
agent that can solve the tasks as well
considering for example the GUI agent
and the choice includes also cost
latency all the or the user experience
that we want to provide to the user uh
in this case in the driver's seat for
example or the passenger and here's an
example where for example the ambiguity
comes like if the user says play some
jazz the media API may be the best if we
have an empty screen but if there's
already a song or a playlist on the
screen then we can also tapping it that
could be also valid choice. So the
ground doesn't have to be just one
label. We can have accept multiple
acceptable valid choices and basically
uh the point is also that the overlap is
real. But this is not the only problem
that we have in engine delegation. Even
when it's implemented as a tool call
agents are not tools. A tool call is
bounded and the agent delegation is
unbounded. So basically delegating to an
agent can start an autonomous loop. It
may reason uh sorry uh it may reason ask
for clarification get stuck resume later
or never return cleanly. So the
orchestration is not just selecting
capability. It's also deciding deciding
when it's safe and useful to let another
loop take over effectively unbounded
control. So we have to uh uh see the
distinguish distinguish between this and
then also with the overlap there's the
ambiguity. So here are some examples
where for example it's clear if I say
navigate me to Munich this is navigation
agent but for example the play some jazz
there are m multiple valid trajectories
multiple valid agents that could solve
the problem so a reliable system should
not basically force it into one
canonical label and it should use the
runtime context and adapt accordingly.
So basically uh it's about the
overlapping agents becoming multiple
valid choices and then it also leads to
consequences in the evaluation. How do
we want to do evaluation and the
benchmark basically should only ask
whether the final task succeeded? No,
it's also about the reasonable path, the
cost, the latency, the user experience
that we want to provide and then we can
accordingly create the data set that
then have also the full runtime context.
And then uh we have the metric for
example sometimes we can optimize for
latency sometimes we can optimize for
the human machine collaboration and
after all it's about also how do we want
to build this multi- aent system in an
enterprise so how I would say like in an
enterprise every team who owns an agent
could build their own benchmark and then
after all multiple teams can put the
benchmarks together and then we can
build a shared benchmark where we also
consider collaboration coordination
patterns and uh basically basically how
everything works together in the
orchestration and delegation benchmark.
So the patterns are just the means uh to
connect the pieces of the multi- aent
system. What matters is making
orchestration paths and delegation
decisions measurable, context aware and
reliable. So keep asking who handles
this work? What path should they take
together? And how do we know it was
good? Thank you.
[applause]
All right. Do we have Christopher
Petrillo with uh Wikipdia Foundation
here? Calling on Christopher. Otherwise,
if you were hoping to hear his talk, we
may need to revisit it later. Is
Christopher here?
Okay, then we will move on to our next
speaker. Nyaki Naar, CEO of uh Sentiment
Proof, transforming from SAS to an
agentic enterprise.
Hello everyone. Good afternoon. Can you
all hear me in the back? I'm not going
up on the stage. I hurt my knee. So, I'm
not going to risk uh climbing up the
stairs. So, I just want to make sure
everyone can hear me.
Okay.
um Nyaki Ner I'm the CEO of site improve
you know the topic I was going to cover
today in the next five minutes is how we
as side improve who have been in the
industry for over 20 plus years
transformed from a traditional SAS
business into what we call the agentic
enterprise especially in the world of
content intelligence if you take a step
back and look at what's really happening
around us we live in an AIdriven world
with infinite content. And when I say
content, you have web content, mobile
content, social content, documents, all
kinds of content that large big global
enterprises struggle with. We have over
5,500 customers worldwide
across global 2000, Fortune 500
companies, across financial
institutions, healthcare,
um public sector, all kinds of various
industries. And one of the key
challenges that every customer that we
talk to has is to make sure that content
is compliant. And when we say content is
compliant, content is accessible.
Especially with EAA, uh European
accessibility act in Europe. In North
America, we have what we call ADA, uh
American Disability Act, requires every
large enterprise to make sure their
content is compliant.
In addition to that problem, compliance
problem, customers also struggling with
what we call content visibility.
You know, in today's day and age where
search has evolved beyond the
traditional searches into the AIdriven
searches. Raise of hands, how many of
you use all the other AIdriven searches
for finding all your content, finding
all your information you're looking for?
I'm sure, right? Pretty much. This is
the agentic conference. So I'm sure all
of you are using uh AIdriven searches.
Uh and the next problem is you know in
this world when everyone is a developer
when everyone can build content when
everyone can design content how do you
ensure that content is compliant and is
performing. So our response and I'll go
through all the various agentic use
cases we built is to shift left is to
address this problem at the time of
creation as developers as designers as
content creators are creating the
content are building apps are generating
more and more designs to be able to
detect those issues upfront during the
creation and remediate those issues.
Which is why last year we released our
what we call our agentic content
intelligence platform across four key
pillars across accessibility agents to
be able to detect issues and auto
remediate those accessibility issues at
the time of creation. Conversational
analytics agents to be able to you can
ask any question it'll automatically
generate your reports and dashboards.
search agents to make sure your content
can be visible in all those AIdriven
searches and content strategy agents for
you to make sure you can do content
briefs, content drafts and all kinds of
content uh descriptions there. And we
also released what we call a MCP server
for us to be able to integrate
agent-gagent in configuration across all
these AIdriven tools across lovables of
the world, co-pilots of the world, VS
codes of the world. And that has really
transformed how we integrations to the
market which used to take maybe I would
say weeks or months sometimes can now be
done in days or even minutes.
So let me do a very quick this is a
recording of a demo that uh we captured
just so that you can see how easy it is
for us to do this integrations. This is
with uh the lovable app that we
integrated
and just asking okay what agents it has
uh access to and it it immediately
detects the various site improve agents
and lovable agents and also the browser
agents and say okay what can you do with
the site improve agents? It'll highlight
the various uh agenda capabilities. We
have our alpha detect agent, our uh AI
rules agent, our auto remediation
agents. And as I'm running this in live,
right? So now let's grab the the URL of
uh this website that you see on the
right hand side and do a quick check,
quick accessibility check. And when I
run that check, you can see it has
highlighted approximately five issues
there. Okay. Now, let me do a quick
prompt for agents to work with each
other. Our uh site improve agents to
work with lovable agents to be able to
quickly detect what those issues are and
auto remediate those issues. As you
know, you can see it's calling the
agents through our MCP server and
detecting what issues it has and it
automatically remediates those issues.
This, ladies and gentlemen, used to take
us anywhere from um weeks to months to
detect these issues and auto remediate
those issues. Now you can see it can
pretty much be done in in minutes.
That's what we mean
is to help our customers all the content
that they have this infinite volume of
content that they have is to keep that
content compliant and performing. It's
not an either our solution for us. It's
an and solution and that's all running
on one single platform. With that, thank
you all.
[applause]
All right, we now have uh Serbia Rathor.
Pardon me for not having your speak. An
agentic AI is a UX problem disguised as
a technology breakthrough.
Okay.
Hey everyone. Uh hope you're having a
good time. Uh we have spent the last day
and majority of the day today talking
about how are we building agents in the
best way, monitoring them, orchestrating
them, evolving them. But uh I'm going to
spend the next 5 minutes giving you a
little different perspective on like the
reason why we're building all these
agents is that consumers trust them to
use and operate. And a lot of this is a
UX problem and not a technology and
model problem. Uh I am the VP of AI
products in a company called Invoka. We
build marketing and revenue agents for
brands which operate in highly
considered purchases. Before I joined
Invoka last year, I was the former CEO
co-founder of a company called symbol.ai
for seven years. Uh our company was
acquired last year and we spent seven
years on the infrastructure bed. We
ourselves spent like a lot of money and
time uh training uh language models
which were very specific to understand
the nuances of humanto human
interactions. And of course like my
hypothesis has massively evolved over
the last one and a half years or one
year since uh deploying these agents uh
and using the models have somewhat
become interchangeable. But really what
matters is how does the design of these
models and the experience with the
consumer will dictate whether whatever
you build the agent that was capable of
performing the workflow actually
influenced in the right moment uh with
the right timing.
So um just to give a little background
and the type of persona I'm talking
about today uh Invoka operates in an
industry called considered purchases
where we work with companies with
healthcare, telco, insurance, home
services uh where the consumer almost
every time needs to speak to a human
before making a purchase decision. Uh
these are not things that you operate on
a day-to-day basis and in these
industries earning trust almost needs to
be instant. uh and agents that operate
in these industries have to emulate the
human trust that the consumers have been
working for years with these brands
almost immediately through the way that
they are interacting with the consumer.
Uh the big problem here is not really to
define workflows and do revenue
operations or do agent e-commerce. The
bigger workflow is to actually win the
user trust that is arriving when they're
interacting with the agents with an
already failed mindset. Like your users
and the consumers that we work with day
in and day out are so skeptical of
interacting with AI agents. And that's
not uh because of like their paranoia
about AI. It's really because of years
of gaps in technology that we have all
been through and failed UX of the
agentic experiences or conversationally
experiences that have been operating for
a long time. So when your user starts
operating with these systems, they're
thinking that oh I'll have to repeat all
the information. This agent doesn't know
anything about me. Uh and uh I'm I'm
just going to say talk to a human and
just get rid of this loop very fast. So
that's why the hardest design problem
isn't making the agent capable. It's
actually making making it trustworthy to
someone that's walked in expecting it to
fail.
So uh we've built um to solve these
problems we have started to build like a
uh a context layer that specifically
informs the UX. Invoka has operated uh
over the last I think 14 years and they
contain huge volumes of call
information, buyer journey data,
interaction data and all that we are
mining to inform the knowledge and the
training of the agents to inform what
intents they operate, what actions they
take and that's all great but we're
building another layer that just informs
the UX of the agent itself and it sort
of falls into three categories. One is
of course like what do you know about
the consumer before the consumer even
types the word which is the contextfed
UX. The second is the graduated agency
where uh at the time where you're
designing the agent you're really giving
the agent the things that it should do
and it should not do uh and designing
the experience for it. And the third is
uh the in- moment um in-moment uh
reading which is actually one of the
most important things because if you
feel that there is urgency or something
off the be off the happy path that a
consumer is facing with how do you skip
the usual normal path and uh design a
workflow that gets the that gets the
consumer a delightful experience in that
moment. So these are just examples and
I'm going to go through quickly because
of time here. But this is an uh an
oncology example. A patient trying to
book an appointment 2:15 after detecting
cancer and not available in the form
fill and instead of taking them through
a painful experience of filling a form,
the agent quickly books an appointment
and confirms availability of doctors for
that. The second one is around uh
prescription refills where the hospital
has implemented a new my chart system.
They want the self-s serve the
experience, but again the timing uh
after 6 p.m. trying to get a refill in
place, left a voicemail, no response,
and the agent quickly diverts them to
the right experience to handle it
quickly. The third one is just an
example of how the same UX can be
applied to support use cases. Although
we've spent a majority of time on
revenue generating use cases where um
someone is uh operating at uh in the in
the morning waiting for a video
interview call in the morning and
internet is down. So, how do you handle
diagnosis not through a 20-step process,
but a five-step self diagnosis and stay
with the call. Um, so yeah, I just uh
because uh we're running short on time,
but just leaving you with this thought
that as you're all designing uh
experiences for your agent, think about
the user experience and really think
about context being uh a key input to
the design system for your agents. Uh
and if you don't have the data, collect
it and build an agentic loop or connect
to systems that actually power that
data. Thank you so much.
[applause]
>> We now welcome Daniel Frink, AI
engineering lead at Cognizant for
scaling up config driven multi-agent
networks with Neurosan.
Thanks everybody. Uh let's see
uh a little bit about uh where I come
from. I'm from Cognizant AI lab. Uh we
are a big R, little D, small group of
maybe 30, 40 people or so. Uh centered
in San Francisco. We got some people in
Bangalore. There's my people. Uh and
what I generally do is I do I take the
research pro uh research problems that
are promising and then push them out so
that they can be scaled up. And the
greatest example of this is like two and
a half years ago, we were experimenting
with multi-agent systems and we quickly
realized that the glue code of agents
calling other agents uh was was the
noise in what we were really trying to
do. And so we wanted to lift that up.
And what we came up with was is now
known as Neurosan. And Neurosan is
basically a a configurationdriven
uh system where you agents can call
other agents. Agents can call coded
tools. Uh coded tools can call back into
the agent system. And all of this is
described in JSON basically except of
course for the code the coded tool
aspect. Every node can in a in the
system describes upward uh to its
upchain uh callers uh what it can do,
what it needs in order to operate in
terms of information, who it can talk
to, and then of course there's the
system props overall. Uh and one of the
bits of secret sauce about what's going
on is that the ultimate upchain is the
user. And when it comes to uh uh secure
credentials and stuff like that, we have
a we have a side channel of data which
we call slide data which allows you to
put in the tokens that you never want to
get in the chat stream basically.
So uh I'm going to focus on the last two
bits here. So early on we actually
figured out that we don't really need to
wait for the next great model in order
to boost our capability. the real uh the
real win is breaking your problems down
so that a smaller model can handle it
and handle it more reliably and more
cheaply for that matter. And the other
interesting thing was that when given
the right tools
uh we had all kinds of people starting
to make multi- aent systems uh even our
marketing people had some really really
great uh really great uh ideas and tools
that they still use today.
So some of the really interesting things
that come from the configurationdriven
aspect of these multi-agent systems
um I'll start with the second one first.
Agentic webs. So if you develop a multi-
aent system, it's actually pretty easy
for that multi-agent system to then call
out to another multi-agent system as a
tool. Add infinite item. We can call MCP
servers, ATA servers, whatever other
agent system you want, we can do that.
Uh the other interesting thing is that
the common tooling for actually calling
our agents in the first place even with
the secrets uh is since that's all
standardized the testing itself becomes
data driven in and of itself. This is
the interaction that I want to have that
becomes data driven and then it gets
even crazier because now because we have
uh it's the JSON files or hookon files
that that describe these agentic systems
they're just forms to fill in. So we now
have uh uh multi-agent systems that are
basically vibe coding other multi-agent
systems and they are they can call them
as a as a thought. They can uh as a as a
perishable thought. They can c they can
then uh be downloaded and used as part
of the overall system. Uh there's some
other stuff on there I'm going to glaze
over. So um how can we apply this stuff?
Sounds kind of fancy. Uh what we're
seeing here is in the center is what we
call the front man. He's basically the
root of the system and he is calling out
to other agents uh that are kind of m uh
middle tier and then and in the center
circle and then in the outer circle is
the um are the actual leaf leaf node
agents that are actually doing uh
actually doing something. So the example
here is a corporate internet. Uh so the
think of your corporate homepage that
you probably look at at least at least
once a week uh if not more and different
departments HR, finance, IT, they all
have different needs. They all have
different agents that actually everybody
kind of needs to kind of needs to uh uh
kind of needs to be able to access. And
so the um
sorry what we do
how do I go back? Here we go. So we have
this prompting infrastructure that's
called AOSA. And the idea is is that the
guy who's who is um who is answering the
the current question, he doesn't know
anything, but he knows who else to call.
And that all contributes contributes
down uh trick trickles down so so that
different aspects of the same question
can be answered by HR by legal yada yada
yada. So the coordinator doesn't know
anything but the people down below do
and then as information comes up there
is a um an aggregation of knowledge that
that happens on the way up. So
we actually convinced our corporate IT
department to help us eat our own dog
food. uh and currently they have about
200 leaf level agents uh coordinated by
this AOSA infrastructure. Everything
from Service Now, Salesforce, Peopleoft,
all the stuff that people know and love.
Uh it scales up ridiculously, which
we're very happy about. Uh and the
results are basically in the ticket
counts. So the blue line that starts in
the kind of upper left of that graph and
kind of goes to the middle middle left
of that graph is is the ticket count.
And the the blue vertical line in the
center there is kind of when things were
deployed actually a little bit to the to
the left. And when we deployed that we
basically found we had about 30 second
or 30% drop in overall tickets because
the agent system was handling requests
better better than people overall. Uh
and
uh the I just want to say that this
stuff is freely available. Uh it's uh
agreeably licensed. Uh we encourage you
to try it out for yourselves and um we
look forward to actually working with
AIF to to make this uh happily available
in in in the Linux Foundation and we're
going to have a site uh bring your own
key site which this whole system
supports where you can uh vibe code your
own multi- aent systems. Thank you very
much.
[applause]
That now brings us to the session for
agent evolution and benchmarks. We'll be
starting with Darshi Raha uh VP and
fellow engineer at Digital Ocean on
preferences, benchmarks, model routing,
and how teams actually build.
Are we going?
Moment.
Okay. Uh are you able to hear me? Okay.
Cool. So I am Dashi. I will describe how
to build an routing system for the
models for the agents that you need. So
before that quickly about me. I am a
fellow engineer at digital ocean. I
joined digital ocean almost a year back.
I am working on data and AI stuff.
Before this I was long time at AWS. I
was working on launching fundamental
services like open search and several
IML services from ground up. So now at
little bit about digital ocean. So
digital ocean is a cloud native AI
native uh full stack cloud service.
You can get everything from the bottom
layer which is infrastructure from
compute to storage to networking to up
the stack data and learning to manage
agents and the inference router is
sitting in the middle inference layer if
you see and it is actually going to
impact everything on top of it. Um so
since we launched the inference service
we have onboarded 70 plus models
including the recently leaderboard
topping Kimik K3 and Opus 5 cloud opus 5
and those are amazing models. I love
them but there is one problem which is
cost. So if you are paying for every
task going to the frontier model then
there is huge cost and every company is
kind of feeling that if you see Uber
kind of exhausted their whole year of
agentic AI budget just for just within
four months. Similarly um Walmart is
trying to cap on the on the the AI
stuff. So every company is feeling that
and the most the top reason for that is
the second one which is fit that you do
not need a frontier model to serve every
single of the request. You can always
look at like using a smaller model or a
medium model for some of the other
tasks. So that way you don't have to pay
the frontier cost for every model. So
that is a fundamental problem that we
are facing and we are seeing this
challenge from all of our customers and
there is an operational problem as well
which is a risk. So if you depend on
just one model then you are risking your
whole application if that one model goes
down or if it degrades.
So all these problems together
um all our customers come to us that hey
how can we reduce our inference bill?
This is not cheap and everyone is put
investing on that one but everyone wants
to reduce the amount. Now let's see how
you can do that. So what actually needs
your uh frontier model capability. So if
you are just doing a classification or
labeling problem, you do not really need
that. You can use a simple model, a
small model to do that. If you are doing
say writing task or summarization task
or um translation task a simple small to
medium model will be fine just fine for
that or if you're doing code code
generation and all maybe a media model
is fine or if you're doing scientific
reasoning the reasoning kind of stuff
that really needs that depth and the
power of the frontier model like medical
things or maybe security analysis for
those things sure you want to use the
frontier model. Um
that's the reason. So we see that
there's huge opportunity here that if
you can direct to some other models and
take the support of other models instead
of frontier model for everything then
you have huge opportunity to reduce your
cost and that's the reason we launched
the inference router which sits in the
middle of your client and the server. So
you do not need to statically code that
hey which model you can choose for which
of the task or um you do not need to
build it yourself. So we have launched
the inference router that is sitting on
the server side and you just define that
for which task which class of task you
want to use which model and then we are
going to intelligently route it to that
model with all the real time feedback
like what is the latency currently what
is the model available is um what is the
cost so with all that real time metrics
input the router in the middle will
decide and appropriately route to the
right model. So some of the uh um
benefits that we are seeing already in
the industry. So we have this customer
lo which is a Canadian law based uh AI
startup. So you can go there for legal
advice. You can subscribe and you if you
have a legal question or something you
can go there and they will give using AI
as well as uh based on the human in the
loop. Now they are seeing 40 to 50%
reduction in inference cost.
So similarly we have seen you can
actually go up to probably 80% of the
cost you can remove you can reduce by
using this router. So that's why like
we're super excited to launch this and
work with our customers to reduce their
cost reduce their utiliz I mean uh model
uh cost and build without without losing
the capability and the quality of the
model and the task output
how much okay so uh that's why this is
becoming the most important part of the
stack this is the latest phops. So I was
at AWS before this and I have seen like
how long it took for the uh cloud cost
optimization to be a real discipline. We
were really putting lot of effort in
during the covid time to reduce the cost
optimize the cost but here it is
happening right now as we speak. It is
not like with waiting. So within one or
two years I have seen like im like
massive shift here.
So uh now let's get the intuition of
what you need to build a model router
service what actually you are looking
for that you you have a task and you
have a lot of prompts and other things
with it in addition to that you also
need to consider the cost that you are
willing to spend the latency that your
application can take. So all those are
dynamic things. Those are not static.
What is the latency? What is the cost
and those things plus of course the
prompt and tool and like lot of things
those are there. Now all these things
combined your inference router should be
capable of routing based on those. Now
those no public leaderboard or public
benchmark tell you. So you need to
encode those in the router so that it is
not based on just the benchmark that hey
this model is best for this task. So
you're blindly routing to that. So you
encode all of those and real time
intelligently route to that.
So now this is how we built it. Um so in
the middle you can see that there's a
plano and there's a routing model on the
top. So this routing model is a
purposebuilt routing model just by us.
And all of this plano and the routing
model both are open source that we are
talking about. So there is no vendor
lock in here. you can use it yourself or
host it or uh even contribute it. So
that will be awesome. But uh the routing
model is a 30 billion parameter model
that is purpose-built just for this
task. And as it is purpose-built and
trained only for this routing task, it
it beats the frontier model u benchmark
just on the routing task like uh GPD 5
series model and all like it has bitten
on that one. Um and so the plano so all
your uh result all your question comes
to plano and plano is a proxy in the
middle the proxy will route it to the
router and it will get the result and
then it will rank. So if you remember I
talked about hey what is the latency you
can tolerate what is the cost you are
willing to spend. So based on cost and
latency it will reank the models that
for this task you have a candidate set
of models it will reank. So that is
totally dynamic it. So the plano
supports the observability from multiple
systems of course like here it is
plugged into digital ocean inference uh
system. So you can plug into any of your
system that you want. So with that it
can get those real time metrics and it
will rerank and route based on that. Now
this is how we think it should be built.
Now there are of course other ways to
build it like for example you can do it
statically like on your homepage you can
have hey for summarization this is a
button and that button is always going
to this model or maybe you can have
coding or translation for translation
you are always sending to this model now
those are super static and you have to
keep updating your client side or in the
client side maybe you can use some other
LLM to decide the routing but then you
are paying double the t tax right you
are increasing the latency by around 600
millcond or so. In addition, you are
also paying more. So you double the tax
just to use another frontier model for
routing. And here this is free. There's
no extra cost. There is no additional uh
cost and latency is only 200 millcond or
less based on the task. So
that's why we believe a purposebuilt
system just for this task is best suited
for router and this sits on the server
side. this is not on the client side. So
you don't need to change client all the
time. Hey, now there's a new model or
now there is a u uh new task that I want
to classify or I want to route. So you
don't need to keep changing your client
side. You just come on the server side.
It is configuration. You just tell on a
natural language what you need. I'll
show you a demo then probably it'll be
more clearer. Uh so this is the system
that we have built and we have open
sourced it. So you guys can put your
hand on it and just try to use it,
improve it. Uh would love that.
So uh this is a little bit about how we
uh how we are u
uh
operationalizing this. So you decide
your rules in natural language and on
top of that there are some presets. So
using public benchmark and using task
specific benchmark we have decided which
model to go what are the candidate
models for a task that is best suited.
So you can start with that preset and
you can of course change it as you go so
that um you and also you plug in your
evaluation. So we also have the
evaluation framework. So you use the
data set that is needed for your company
for your task not someone else public
leaderboard. So you plug in that eval
and make sure that it is the router is
working fine on that data set. If not
then you come back you adjust and then
you have the loop to make it fine-tuned
for working on your system better.
Um so there's uh I talked about
preference our router. What I mean by
that is you decide your preference that
you this is the latency you can
tolerate. This is the cost you want and
based on that the router routes it. Now
there's a cash hour routing part that I
have not discussed. I have I'm running
on low running low on time. So quickly
let me tell. So cash hour routing you
must consider because if suddenly on the
let's imagine agentic system when you
are writing code and is automatically
discovering code, analyzing code,
writing code. So all of those there lot
of prompt that are same on that agent
system. In every loop there is the same
prompt. Now if you suddenly in the
middle of the session if you suddenly
change the model then you're going to
lose the warm cache that the model was
already having. So you don't want to
have that. So you want to have the cash
hour routing. This is something we are
uh doing right now. Uh watch it decide
live. So I wanted to show a demo. I
don't know how much time I have. We two
two and a half minutes. Okay. Let me
quickly try that. Um so this will make
it like something like very uh concrete
for you. So you come to digital ocean
you just click on create router you just
give a name let me give a name quickly
test uh some description now this is
where you add task and I'm just for the
sake of time I'm adding a preset task
let's say summarization and save it
that's all now let's see if the Wi-Fi
will work
I do not see it is saving so I don't
think the Wi-Fi is working but anyways
what happens is that um so you see there
are all these tasks so all for each of
the task there is a set models you
cannot tune the model and you can then
decide you want to rank by cost or
latency or that kind of thing. So when I
was a Wi-Fi was working now there is a
playground just in with one click the
router will be launched immediately and
with one click you can launch it in the
playground and compare with another
model like let's say opus 5 and just
before this I was trying it out so if
you run the router versus the opus 5 so
router was around I think 20 uh times
cheaper or so than opus 5 and it also
completed the task around 67%
faster. So that was the result. I wish I
would I would have loved to show that
but it is not working. But anyways let
me come back to this one. So uh now just
going to summarize some quick facts. So
as I mentioned the router is a the model
is a purpose-built model. It is only 200
millisecond or less latency it will add
on the server side. It is a 30 billion
purposebuilt model. It is zero
application code change as you need that
I told. Yeah. And uh it is free. It is
completely free. So there is no you are
not paying any double tax. So if you're
using an LLM as I mentioned, you have to
pay double tax for both uh the latency
and the cost. There is no double tax tax
on it. Is completely free to use on
digital ocean or you can also host it on
yourself. Um now just to summarize
everything. So I mentioned about eval
that you have to plug in the eval on
that so that you know that it is working
fine on your data set and of course
there's a caching is a very big thing
that I told and personalization this is
I am super excited I myself have
launched a personalization service
before and here what I mean by
personalization is the more you use the
router and the inference the better it
becomes because if you enable the log
and traces then all those feedback in
the continuous loop and check on the
eval and it continuously improves. So
that is awesome. Without doing anything,
you're not building anything on your
side. Without doing anything, the router
is improving. So that that's where I
want to leave you. Maybe so this is
something we are working on. Maybe next
time we can do a deep dive on that one.
Uh with that uh that's all. So uh please
use it. Try scan the Q your code if you
want to use it. Come to digital ocean
router and just see how it helps you to
reduce the cost. I think this is a
fantastic feature you all should be
thinking about. Um and yeah, come meet
me after the session if you have any
questions. Thank you so much. [applause]
>> We now have Emily Zu with head of
enterprise AI at scale AI on the exam
before enterprise deployment.
Thanks.
Thanks. Thanks for the intro. Uh yeah,
uh currently I'm working at skill AI
head AI functionality within enterprise.
I really enjoyed opportunity to talk to
many of the enterprise customers. Uh
before scale AI, I spent 11 years at
Google. I'm a core member of Jamnai
team. In addition to contributing to
Gemini development, the most relevant
experience I have is I built a team to
do the cloud agent benchmark for Gemini.
So um part of this talk really kind of
uh capture a lot of the observations and
reflections I have uh with this
different roles and the talk is about
the exam before the enterprise
deployment
forward. Okay. So at this moment we're
all from AI communities and um we
there's one thing we all know the value
of AI will have to land to produce
productivities for our real economics uh
impact and that is not going to be
happening if AI stays in the demo and
pilot. We need to have all the AIs to be
deployed from pilot into production. And
so this talk is really about how we get
there from pilot to production. What is
the gating decisions people needs to
make? And the question really is can
this agent be reliably deployed to do
useful work inside of our organization.
So since we talk about benchmark and
then we just start with um benchmarks
right now I don't know how many
benchmarks you are actually aware of how
many bench out there right there's
hundreds of benchmarks out there but if
you look at those benchmarks and we we
use that all the time one thing you
actually would realize is they really
measure ceiling it measures the gap
between what the model able to do right
now and the top of the human int
intelligence, right? And then when you
de if you are a benchmark developer,
when your benchmark have a lower score,
you feel pretty excited because your
benchmark is facing developers, model
developers as your customer. When they
see a lower score on the benchmark, they
feel there's a gap, there's room,
there's things they need to do. They
feel very excited about it. But if you
bring the same benchmark to enterprise
buyers, they have a completely different
view. And I can share an anecdote with
you guys. Um so when you talk to
enterprise customer we have actually a
particular use case tax to SQL. The
executives they don't understand why
your agent would not be able to actually
get 99% of the reliability given
everybody saying agent so so smart now
and then the researchers going to show
them all text to SQL benchmarks. I don't
know whether you guys know what's the
top of the text to SQL benchmark.
They're only 60 70%. Because people
don't wish their benchmark get
saturated. When the benchmark is
saturated, people don't use it anymore.
But the reality is for enterprises they
really want to see that number how to
get that number into 95 99%. So that is
actually totally different mindset
things. So this is what we say the gap
is where the current benchmark really
measured capability. You see a score,
you run all the models and the model
compete on it. It's really developer
facing. But what actually need for
enterprise adoption is a deployment
readiness is say you know is this use
case ready for deploy is what it takes
for it to deployed and this is what
we're going to talk about.
All right.
Okay. So before that we'll just like go
through five um very basic questions
that enterprise buyers ask. The first
one is um what is ready for pro
production today? We have a list of
priorities but among all of this which
is hard which is relatively ready for me
to deploy and the second thing is how
can I actually measure readiness because
readiness is a concept how can I
quantify it and how can I trust the u
the outcome um but more importantly um
if there's a gap if it's not 99% let's
say it's 90% doesn't matter how it's
measured or covered later how can I
actually fill the gap of 90 uh the 10%
because my I can't go with 90% % for
production I always need 99.9 999 point
reliability for my product to be
deployed to facing the customer. What do
I do to fill the gap? Um and it's
actually not surprising because right
now there's always the human oversight.
The question is what is the human
oversight policy that can use in order
to get in there and there's also there's
also question about um the cost because
you know if you have agent you have
tokens on this side and now you also
have human on the other side as of
together am I actually saving money from
the AI initiative
okay so overall um the readiness profile
really talks about um how can we do
qualification what's the risk envelope
what's the oversight policy policy and
um what is the improvement path to get
from where we are to what we want to be.
Okay, so now let's get a little bit more
concrete um from the questions how could
we actually get evaluation primitives.
Okay, so the first one
is
can we trust the answers?
So one agent produce the answer for us.
What would be the evaluation primitives
that allows us to actually um evaluate
the answer trustworthiness? I think this
is no secret. Um essentially it is
grounding um how we actually measure the
citation pre uh precision for every for
every piece of information in the
answer. Is it grounded into a source
piece of information? Um, do we actually
cover everything within our evidence
database to produce? Do we miss
anything? The recall problem.
The next one, couldn't actually see this
very well.
It's the policy compliance problem.
A lot of the cases the agents give you a
right answer. But question is, does it
follow my internal policy? I'll give you
a very concrete example. um in working
with one of the health care customers,
they would like us to actually do a
quality auditing for um that for uh
clinical safety events. The safety event
would say can we identify clinical um
acute kidney failure accurately and in
order to identify that they basically
say you have to look at the labs you
have to look at the increase of cryotin
in the lab measurement to get it. But
when when we deploy our agent we see the
agent is become smart. It does a
shortcut. What it does is instead of
uh retrieve retrieval the cryotin
measures from the lab measurement what
it does is it actually just look at the
clinical notes look at the diagnosis
notes within electronic micros system to
say whether this person has acutic
kidney failure. So it doesn't really
follow the policy that is specified the
clinical environment to do the job and
that's actually a problem we need to
address. Um then the third question
my favorite question is does the agent
know what it doesn't know? This is
actually super important and two things
related with it. One is the confidence
calibration. A lot of cases the agent
would say I'm confident 60% of time
right but is it really then you really
need to calibrate the confidence that's
self-claimed by the agent to the reality
is it really 60% of time it is producing
the right answer that's a calibration
question but more importantly is if it
doesn't know you know we need to give
them a policy to see when you should
stop g answers you need to upstain you
should say hey I need human rights I
need to pass it over so this is the
Third thing that we need to evaluate to
answer the question. Okay, I have two
minutes but I I'll be fast. Um
the um the right operations. This is
where the agent system we develop
interact with the traditional enterprise
system because when you have your agent
system is not just about the security
reliability of your system is when the
operations from your agent is actually
getting to enterprise system. How do you
manipulate? How do you mutate the state
of your enterprise system? Is it
recoverable? Is it the rollback policy
there? And the last one is the oversight
economics. And this is what are talking
about if you have human oversight there
in combination is the economics actually
makes sense.
Okay. So
all right
putting the primitive into a framework
that can how we actually organize
evaluation primitives into a a a thought
framework. So this is kind of a surface
we're using in our upcoming benchmark
coming up this week uh this month. Um
the first one is we actually think about
really about the the surface where the
agent is interacting with uh the uh the
agent system is interacting with the
enterprise system. The first one is
inside we just get information for human
review and the policy is really about
human review policy. Um what you do is
you you get a rate operations and you
want to see whether the question we want
to verify is whether the answer is
trustworthy. The second surface is
actually your agent system is
interacting with your enterprise system.
The question is whether you change it in
a way that is recoverable, trustworthy.
It are you actually doing it in a
privacy preserving way without leaking
your information. Do you do it in a way
that you permutate you chain uh mutate
your system in a trustworthy way so
that's recoverable. The last one is
we're getting there really fast. So the
last one is um open conversation. It's
not just interacting with your
enterprise system but interact with your
enterprise customers in the open
conversation way. In this environment
the input is from open space end users.
They could give you malicious um
misspecified information. How do you
actually steer the conversation to
achieve your goal? So that's the three
kind of uh vulnerability um or
evaluation services. So with that being
said, um the deployment profile really
answer a list of questions. Um seven of
them. I'm not going to repeat them, just
read off the slides. Um I want to
respect the time and then just really go
to the the final two slides. Really two
things I want to call out here is in
enterprise benchmark what people really
want is not a a number to say what's the
score of it. What you would like to do
is to to have is really two things. The
first thing is is this use case ready?
But meanwhile, what you actually want to
understand is what is the economics? How
much what's the cost I need to pay to
form a human oversight policy so that I
could achieve my reliability right there
and the path to improvement is not a
score improvement. It's not say I'm
having the score from 60% to 80% 90%.
The path for improvement is economical
change in the sense that initially you
need a heavy human oversight but over
the time with the improvement model
quality is actually the cost you pay for
this task is is reducing. We are
constrained by reliability. Reliability
is not something you can trade off. What
is trade-off is what's the policy needs
to be there. How human and agent to work
together together in a trustworthy way.
And this is my last slide. Don't only
ask how intelligent agent is. Ask what
is ready to do under what constraint and
what's the risk and what's the cost. And
that's I hope I'm right on time. Thank
you. [applause]
Now we have Jen Wuang Wang, assistant
professor, University of Santa uh
California, Santa Cruz, a research
adviser for scale AI. From training to
evaluation, open recipes for building
agentic AI at scale AI.
>> [snorts]
>> Yeah, maybe go back a little bit to the
Okay.
Oh, I should do it. Okay. Uh, yeah.
Hello everyone. Uh, my name is uh
Chinua. I'm currently a assistant
professor at UCSC and uh in the meantime
I'm also I think working with Emily also
closely at the scale as a research
advisor. Um so today I'm going to talk
about uh basically um the post training
to evaluation what we've been working on
right try to build a frontier hopefully
agents uh you know using what we have
already uh at the scale AI um let's get
started so um I think I can spend a
little bit time on talking about if you
guys don't know scale AI right so the
mission of the company is really just
try to build the reliable AI systems. Um
I think for the uh world's most
important decisions I think is founded
by in 2016 uh and it's pretty big right
now with many employees and the the
offices across I think US and also in u
I think other countries as well. Um but
I will get straight to today's topic. I
think I will mainly cover uh I think
mainly two topics. one is a post
training right as as part of the in the
title briefly but only briefly because
we only have 10 minutes I think the sec
second part will be talking about
evaluation and I try to uh bring some
synergy between those two components
right um so I will start just with the
uh a general idea about uh the current
research focus at a scale uh on the post
training part which is trying to right
so like a research train is also like
this right moving from RLHF to Rubik's
based RL right so I think this is a
practice we got from you know basically
working with the frontier labs to
providing the data services and we
figure out this is something really
important for post training um so
there's definitely challenges over there
right how to really design effective
reward and how to use that reward with
RL and how to make reward even better
during a training during in the RL
phrase right so we have been publishing
I think at I clear this year SML I think
hopefully we get something also at the
new so on so forth in in middle of the
response but uh um we are able to I
think push a boundary of gRPO right by
using a Rubik's based reward paradigm
right just basically improve the
performance and is able to uh I think
also get some I think interesting
receipt or uh you know basically uh
insights I think from the uh from the
process of uh training and also working
with the data uh how to basically play
with this fly flywheel right the data
and RL part hopefully I can guess
something u you know uh for the takeaway
for you guys today right so the first
thing I want to focus on is really this
our recipe we actually realize it's
important I really want to highlight or
avocado this is uh bas basically the uh
Rubik's based reward right so this is
important because I I think in general
right so if you want to make RL work uh
right so previously I think the train is
on the so-called variable domain right
where you can pretty much know for
example coding or mass you can pretty
much know whether this is true or force
right you pretty much get a a ground
truth verification right but in many
real world cases uh where we really care
about where you know Frontier Lab really
care about is really uh you want to make
this work for domains where there's no
verifier right whereas it's it's not a
verifiable domain so we need to find out
a way to make it work for those
openended doain could be science could
be something else right um could be for
our personal tasks uh so we are trying
to basically set up this paradigm where
we ask right basically uh basically
criterioning or evaluation query
criterion and turn that uh you know into
verification right something like that.
So we are able to really uh I think uh
build a new reward model which is not uh
on basically distinguish
uh better response you know versus a
worse response we are trying to say
which one is backing basic better and is
ranking based from Rubik's so it's it it
can scale up to real world scenarios and
we build a a reliable pipeline uh like
we show I think in these two figures
where we can start with something simple
and gradually build build a very high
quality Rubik and use that in RL freeze
and we witness improvements on
open-ended tasks um right that's a
takeaway and then this is a natural
extension of the first first work right
is also on Rubik's where you train a
model but the policy will change right
your policy becomes better better right
better better code um right so but
there's still something uh you know is
changing so you have a reference policy,
you have some current policy and you
figure out what is missing in the
counter reward and generate better
Rubik's or online rubik where you can
integrate this into the reward model
where then you you can pretty much just
train a better better and be more robust
to downstream tasks. So this kind of
online Rubik's I think evolution uh I
think aligns very closely with the
recent trend in uh I would say uh self
or improvement or recursive
self-improvement line of work right we
are moving towards there and the second
part um I think that's pretty much um I
just want to highlight a few research
done the post training and I think in
the evaluation space I think it's
definitely uh scale's main focus is
really um basically driving those
insights from the training and talking
to the customer and then uh build some I
think the worst you know basically
worldwide leaderboard for those frontier
models to to to be on right so there's
many uh going on but uh I would just
want to highlight a few projects
recently right so um many of you guys
definitely it's like a really uh working
demo of agents right it's like a survey
agents or coding agents right I think a
scale invest a lot in this domain try to
build a reliable benchmark to try to
understand uh whether uh you know what's
the true capability of the uh agents
right of sway agents I think you guys
know the benchmark such as su bench sway
bench pro where you can pretty much just
think about the problem is like there's
some uh text description about the
problem uh in the GitHub and you just
need to ask agent to generate a patch
which can eventually just fix whatever
bug in the original repo, right? But I
think in the real world is much messier,
right? We're um I think as an engineer,
we are not only just looking at the PR
and looking at the issues and generate
uh basically response, right? As a
patch, you need to deal with those uh
writing a unit test. Sometimes you need
to uh even uh figure out problem by just
basically go back and forth looking at
the ripple, ask some question and answer
that question so we can figure out what
to do next. So that will be some insight
we can borrow very differently from
working with benchmarks uh such as su
bench bench pro. Uh so we released this
new benchmark called su atlas right. Uh
I think it's widely adopted by frontier
model frontier labs right now. And uh uh
other than su another I think focus of
the uh invalu agent eval we are building
is in this professional reasoning domain
or this kind of AI for science domain. I
think uh definitely uh you know I don't
need to say too much about hie which is
a like a professional reasoning
benchmark. I think people are still
trying to heal climbing right try to
become better better from different like
a model uh model uh model model families
right and also uh we are also working on
this drug discovery bench which is
trying to really build some real world
healthc care environment uh where uh you
know we we we just work with experts
generous real world uh basically uh drug
discovery uh tasks where we start from
the concept and then deliver the uh
actually the the drug we we recently
also released a preprint on that regard
um and we are also working on two use
right so there's a debate on what is the
best uh I think two interface uh is this
CLI or this MCP I think uh we get a
interesting uh I think uh conclusion
just high level we find out once a model
becomes really capable like a recent uh
um you know cloud 4.8 or GPT 4 5 5.5 or
5.6 six that doesn't matter. Um so model
will learn to use the best tool
interface possible possibly right in in
in a real world scenario. So that really
doesn't matter unless you uh basically
you give the same backend to right um
that the interface really doesn't
matter. Um and then we are also working
on this computer use agents right we are
trying to benchmark computer use use
agents. So we are trying to scale up the
computer use agents environment
benchmark because each each of the
computer use agent benchmark is really
very expensive to run right is marty
model and there's many many I think uh
details you need to consider in terms of
verifications. So we think about a way
to actually based on some existing high
quality uh benchmark and really just
generate long horizon more challenging
more real world tasks from based on
those existing benchmarks. Uh I think we
show that we can pretty much bring down
the performance of the original OS world
where I think the state of art of this
uh I think opus new version is something
definitely beyond 80% bring it down to
something 30%. Um so there is a way we
can construct real world uh data sets uh
syntheatically but in a very high
quality way. Um um this is pretty much
what I want to just final slice
technical slides where we can pretty
much build a synergy between evaluation
and post- trainining right just draw
insights from post training and try to
build a better RO environments and also
draw insights from evaluation failure
mode and try to build a better uh post-
trainining algorithms. Hopefully this
can run forever. So we got those better
evol and a better training result as
well. Um so just closing I think scale
is working with many different frontier
labs governments and also enterprise and
robotics right on this physical AI and
another advertisement I think we got
this third edition of the agency in the
wild uh workshop accepted at new rips
right the deadline coming soon in the
end of this month uh I'm one of the co
uh core organizers there so we have a
wonderful panel of speakers panelist
just Don is there, Joshua is there, uh
Jav is there. So, uh you know, feel free
to submit and see you guys at uh Sly.
Yeah, that's it. Thank you.
Next, next we have Jayen Juan, a PhD
senior AI engineer at Postman on
measuring API agent reliability for long
horizon tasks in production.
Let me see how this works.
Oh, how to go back. Okay, wait.
Is there any way to get make it go back?
Okay, never mind. Uh, could you go back
to first slide? Yes, thank you. Okay.
Hi, this is one. Uh, I'm a engineer from
Postman. So, today I'm going to present
our benchmark called API flow bench. So
for enterprise when a company they use
the AI agent to do a long horizon task
they already facing a issue that a small
mistake made by AI agent at the early
stage can cause the whole text fail. Uh
yeah and then when engineer build the
product for the service people usually
doing the task like uh connecting the
building job to a monitoring API right
and also like creating a record or
recover from the ray limit. Um so our
bench that included those kind of task
to evaluate the models and so what we
found is on the single API task most of
the model even the line model uh they
can they are very good at the
performance they can reach like um 88%
and 97%. So that looks the problem
solved. But the thing is when we connect
those single task together into a long
dependent chain task then the score drop
to 44% 73%.
So the task itself didn't getting
harder. But if the later task is depend
on the results of the previous task the
earlier task then that's where the model
start to fail. So in an enterprise the a
lot of businesses logic is wrapped in
API and now we are wing AI agent into
those APIs. So a small error caused by
AI can become a big problem in the later
time. And nowaday
can the model answering question that's
a job you all you guys all know it and
the real problem is can the AI agent
stay correct cross a long horizon
of dependent chain task. So that's the
difference between answering as and
executing. Um so we
um let's go to next one. Okay. Um okay
here is um so one or two failure mode is
not enough. We want a minimum set that
covers the real API works. So in our
benchmark we break the API works into
seven failure mode. um authentication,
discovery, schema repair, multi-step
execution, error recovery, pagionation,
the stiffness and we grade each of them
separately because they failing for
different reasons like the Stephan for
example um the agent update something at
say step three and then step 15 only
works if the agent save the updates at
the step three. So a model failing at
stiffness has totally different reason
than failing at pagenation and we
gradient we grade them differently. So
it can tell us why the model fails.
Okay. We approximate real users workflow
with inside data and we build a
simulated enterprise API ecosystem and
that mimics the real company's API and
then we generate task on top of it. So
here is a our test generation pipeline
and we start from the enterprise API
ecosystem generation at the step zero.
Then we follow those nice steps to
generate task one by one and each
generate task we have a validation step.
So we use the frontier model to try each
task 10 times and we only keep the task
if pass three times. So why we are doing
that? Because when we use the language
model to generate task um some task are
just not solvable at all. So we don't
want to generate a bunch of unsolover
task and then use those to evaluate
frontier model and claim out there the
limit of the models. So if a task fail
the validation we feed the trial
transcript and the code to a fixer agent
and this fixer will fix the task and we
rerun those 10 trials again. And then if
we keep failing we discard a whole new
one and regenerate new one. So that's
how we make sure each task we generated
are solvable and reasonable. So this
bench is constructed by um an API
ecosystem. The task on top of it one
shared harness and the greater that
score each trials.
So for the harness
uh we designed seven tools. So they work
on five different entities. So each task
and every trial run on the same harness
but just with different ecosystem and
different graders.
So for the greater uh we have three
validator. So two are deterministic one
check the final state of the
environment. One check the final answer
the air agent provided. So we use those
two to grade each trials. So that's the
pass rate you guys can see in our
leaderboard and we also use the language
model validator. So that's not part of
the score but we use it to flag the
doubtful pass so human can review it.
So to make the generated task
trustworthy uh we designed three gates
and each gates kind of avoid different
kind of failing during the task
generation. So the first gate is called
self- testing. A blank submission should
always fail and we if we use the
reference answer but we subtage the
evidence then this grade should always
fail otherwise there's a problem in the
task or validator and second gay is
called solvability so remember I
mentioned we use the frontier model to
try the each task turn times and we only
keep three passes task so that's how we
make sure the task are solvable and then
third one is golden replay so when we
build a chain task
um we put all the reference answer from
each subtask together and then append
them into this chain task and issue all
pass. So that's how we make sure this um
formed final chain text is actually
correct and it's working as we what we
want.
So for the experiment we run um 467 t
test across 13 general world and
eventually we got 11 20 step longchain
task in our bench. So we evaluated 19
models. We run five for each model each
trials. So in total we got around 44,000
trials and all the transcripts are
available in our leaderboard. You guys
can check it online. Uh we are planning
to expand the number of task and also
the length of the chain task in the next
version. So here is the leadable results
for this 20 train tasks. Uh so GBD 5.5
is on the top and orange bars are the
open source model and purple bars are
the closed models. Uh we actually have
this leaderboard updated with this week
and we have Kim K3 and the Fab Five also
included. You guys can check that
online. Um
so
I would say okay I think I jumped a
little bit but it's fine. So an
interesting finding that we found is
right now at this time point the open
source model actually approaching the
top group of the closed model like in
our bench the GRM the QN 3.7 plus also
reach the uh second and third position.
So um
let me okay here. So here are three
takeaways. Um first I would say right
now all the line models even the um all
the models even the light model they are
very good at single task. So they all
got high pass rates in our solo task in
our leaderboard. But so we cannot reveal
the gap between them and that's why we
create this chain test to test their
limit. So we saw the case a lot of it
happens a lot that a model made a small
tiny mistake at the early stage and then
that tiny mistake becomes a broken
report at the later task. So second when
you guys generate synced task always use
the hard to make sure the task you
generated are trustworthy. So when I say
hard gate the example could be like 10
times trial must has at least three
passes that's how idea you guys can
figure out more way and also use the
golden replay to make sure your
reference answer is actually working and
the third one is both the deterministic
validator and the language validator are
needed. So when you create a validator
or grader use be sure to use human in
the loop to keep polishing your
generator because a wrong validator
cannot reveal the true performance of
the models.
Okay here um that's all for this
present. Uh so the blog and readerboard
are all available at blog.postman.com.
If you are interesting whether your API
are agent ready uh come talk to me after
this session. Thank you.
And now we have Rahul Krishna, senior
research scientist at IBM software
innovation labs on scarfbench. Can
agents migrate enterprise Java?
All right. Hi uh hello everyone. Uh I'm
I'm Rahul Krishna. I am a senior
research scientist at IBM research. Uh
my talk today is going to be about uh
enterprise Java applications and how
effective agents are in migrating them
from one framework to another and
modernizing them. So enterprise Java is
um applications in enterprise Java and
modernization outlive the um
outlive the frameworks in which they're
originally written and it's a large um
can you make that a little larger for me
slides.
Thank you.
All right, refract. Um, okay. I think
the slides are slides off. Do you mind
if I grab my laptop and present
Okay, sorry about that.
So, uh, enterprise applications that are
written in Java remain critical. Uh
legacy applications were written in
frameworks and the applications
themselves often outlive the the
frameworks and modernization is an
important use case because it's
important for us to modernize the
application into newer frameworks so
that they have supported runtimes bit
better security deployment modalities
among others. uh but the key insight of
deployed applications is the
institutional knowledge that have been
embedded in the application over several
decades. These include business rules um
data semantics workflows and
integrations and migration must replace
the underlying technology stack rather
than the uh while preserving the
application behavior. Now this is
challenging because the Java frameworks
with which many legacy Java applications
are written um hide the runtime
behaviors with their APIs. So the these
means they use different proxies,
reflections in interceptors and the code
itself doesn't really capture any of
these and these are taken care of by the
framework themselves. And as a
consequence there is not really a
onetoone equivalence between an
application written in let's say spring
to that written in Jakarta.
And when we migrate these applications
it might seem like they um they build
correctly and they run correctly but
there might be silent failures that will
only show up at deployment time. Just to
kind of ground this benchmark and why
this is relevant, I wanted to show this
slide here uh which kind of lays out the
architecture of a typical Java
enterprise application. So large
applications are usually um organized in
tiers and each tier addresses a specific
concern. uh presentation layer for
example presents the application to you
through a browser or a phone application
and all the way down we have data access
layer which uh does database reads and
writes and a crosscutting concern which
ties them all together with
configuration security and so on. But
this is a really challenging problem
because if you look at the application,
a lot of these behaviors and the um the
business logic that's embedded in these
applications are usually hidden behind
framework um and their APIs and each
framework have their own idiosyncrasies.
For example, dependency injections,
annotations and so on in the application
um dictate how the um how the uh
business logic is embedded. And if we go
hunting for it in the code, we may not
find any of these. Even though these
layers are uh separate in terms of their
concerns, a deployed application has all
of these layers interacting with one
another often at the same time and
therefore this is a challenging problem.
Now in order to solve this uh we built
scarfbench which stands for
self-contained application refactoring
benchmark and the objective is twofold.
First, we wanted to see how effective
agents are in migrating applications and
modernizing them from one framework to
another. And second, in the process of
doing this and understanding agent
trajectories, we wanted to build a field
manual of sorts on understanding how to
build agentic solutions for general
modernization.
And we broke this benchmark down into
two groups. I'll quickly go over them.
So, we have focused applications and
whole applications. Focused applications
are self-contained apps for a for a
single layer that we just discussed and
whole applications puts them together
into a cohesive business use case.
Uh this is just a highle overview of uh
of the applications. So what we did at
IBM is we had a lot of subject matter uh
experts manually convert each of these
applications that I've listed here
across all of these frameworks um
through Spring, Quarkus and Jakarta. And
each row here is an application and a
unit of migration could be any app from
one framework to another. And the
objective of doing so is twofold. One,
um, each migration has its own
idiosyncrasies and they're asymmetric in
the sense that spring to quarkus is very
different from jakata to spring. And we
also wanted to see how effective agents
are in um tackling independent layers.
Um agents might be really good at
converting presentation [clears throat]
layer but they might struggle at the
integration or data dependency injection
layer. Um like I mentioned each of these
layers are isolated but a typical
deployed application is a collection of
all of these layers and often these
applications have all of them
communicating with one another and
interacting with one another. So the
whole application part of our benchmark
captures many of these applications both
as a monolith and equivalent deployment
as a microser which again subject matter
experts manually converted across all of
these frameworks.
So at a glance we have about 38
applications individually but this
translates to 114 variations of the same
applications and directed
transformations add up to about 228. But
the key distinction here is the
handwritten test cases. So as we
migrated each of these applications, the
developers wrote test cases for the
behaviors that they expect in the
applications when they're deployed. And
these test cases vary all the way from
uh HTTP checks that I'll show in a
second to see if the app is hosted in
HTTP and HTTPS all the way down to GSP
pages to see if the deployed application
browser click actions and the data is
propagated correctly. So here's a simple
smoke test and there are many of these
that I list but this is a curl test that
just ensures that the deployed app in
the target framework has the same HTTP
ports open and it's uh it's more of a
health check but the smoke test in our
benchmarks also capture if messaging
works correctly if database updates
commits and roll back behave as as
expected and for apps that have a
browser endpoint we also have playright
tests that ensure that the user actions
on the migrated application look
identical to the source app.
Um in doing this we also evaluated um a
large number of coding agents. More
results are in the paper. We discussed
some taxonomies failure modalities but a
quick highlight here is that although
applica agents are really effective at
migrating applications ensuring that
they compile and they can deploy uh
they're they're not really good at behav
um maintaining the behavior in the
target application. What we noticed is
after migration only 2 to 14% of the
migrations actually had the exact same
behavior that the source application had
and compilation itself was a weak signal
because that gave us a false indication
that the agents are really good at
migration but the behavior was not
preserved and the flows here also
strongly suggest that some frameworks
are really hard to migrate to and some
frameworks are really hard to migrate
from. So there is an inherent um
complexity and asymmetry in how agents
migrate from one application to another.
There are more details in the paper uh
various failure modalities and some
instructions on how agents can be better
um better built. Uh so here's a
benchmark. Um feel free to reach out to
me after the talk and I'd be happy to
answer any questions. Right. Thank you.
Now we have Grace Tang, AI at Hex on
Data Benchmarks, where everything's made
up and the points don't matter.
Hi everyone. Um, I'm Grace. I do AI
research at Hex. We are a AI data
analytics platform and as such I spend a
lot of my time basically trying to get
LLM to um like do data analytics and
data science better which is really hard
and and so a big part of what we think
about is eval experimentation.
And lately every time I look at a new
public benchmark for data I'm kind of
struck by the same thing.
Everything's made up and the points
don't matter. Roll credits. We're done.
I'm just kidding. But what do we really
mean by this? Well, today I'm going to
talk a little bit about data benchmarks,
where they are doing well and where we
might be missing the mark. My thesis on
benchmarking agents is very simple and
it's very much like what a lot of people
talked about today. We should be testing
these agents in environments that have
the same level of realism as their
eventual deployments. And as you'll find
today, data is a uniquely poorly modeled
field in frontier benchmarking. So
before we get into that though, what
does a real frontier benchmark look
like? You all might have heard of some
of these um like program bench. You're
rebuilding a common codebase from
scratch. No internet, just docs. Running
a vending machine business and then just
evaluating your profit at the end.
Or like these, you know, simple yet
challenging web search questions. These
are actually only around 30% sellable by
humans.
What do all of these great frontier
benchmarks have in common? Well, they're
evolves that actually test real world
behavior that we care about these agents
being able to do. The problems are hard
for agents and they're hard for people
as well.
Now though, let's take a look at the
field of data analytics.
DSBench. Last year, OpenAI used DSBench
to report that their agent surpassed
human performance by a significant
margin on realistic data tasks. Ready to
see what these realistic tasks look
like?
Well, a bunch of them are like these
multiplechoice exam questions about
financial modeling. It's literally like,
can you write the SQL? Can you tell me
what Excel formula you should use? And
then there's like a bunch of public
Kaggle pro uh projects including like
the Scrabble word puzzle. It's totally
crazy. Um and I think data analysts will
tell you that this is not what their
work looks like on the day-to-day. If
this is what your work looks like, I'm
sorry.
What about spider 2? I think Emily from
scale mentioned this one earlier, but we
have a number of text to SQL benchmarks.
These though, I think the main issue
with this is that it's not really
testing analytics. If you look at it,
the English is very specific. It's very
prescriptive. You're basically just
mapping like English to wear clauses.
It's like a translation task or an
instruction following task. And the
external knowledge is not exactly
carefully curated either. It's the wrong
sport.
What about dabstep? This is a well-known
set. And uh this question looks very
straightforward. It's like pick a
multiple choice question. What's the top
country for fraud? [snorts] The problem
though is that if you actually pull the
data for this, the question is kind of
fundamentally underspecified. It doesn't
tell you whether you're looking at fraud
rate, fraud volume. And like a real data
analyst might produce something that
looks more like this chart. And arguably
that's more complete and correct.
And so all of this is very hard. I I
don't want to dunk on everyone's work.
They've done a lot of hard work here.
But overall, these themes tend to
emerge. Nine is too many for me to read
out loud. But the main idea is that
they're not realistic. These grading is
really, you know, harsh. It's grounded,
not really in reality.
So, at Hex, we have built Shorelane.
Now, Shorelane is completely made up.
The points don't matter either. I'm not
saying we figured it out, but it is
pretty cool, and we try and address some
of these realism issues. We built a
fully synthetic B2B SAS company called
Shorelane Commerce. It's got a lot of,
you know, semantic pitfalls that might
occur in a real business. It's messy. It
has migrations and incomplete
documentation and the task well we have
these agents do realistic tickets that
an analytics agent uh or analytics
person in real life might do. We
evaluate on the entire train of thinking
on the tool efficiency and the actual
analytics that's going on.
And still though this is only half the
problem. These evolves are still
suspended in a moment in time. How can
we allow data analytics to learn from
their mistakes? Well, unfortunately,
that's pretty much the time I have for
today. So, if you're interested in
hearing more, please follow us at
hex.te. You can also always reach out.
And if you're interested on working with
us, please reach out at our careers
page. Thank you so much.
[applause]
And now we have a random set. I'm a
principal ML engineer at Janentech on AI
data readiness evaluations framework.
>> Trying to figure out this works. Okay.
Hi everyone. Um,
oops. I think I'm going the wrong
direction.
[snorts]
How is this? Okay, great.
>> Hi everyone. Uh, I'm Orindam and I'm a
principal machine learning engineer in
genetic. My focus areas are agentic AI,
scientific AI in life sciences and u AI
data readiness and also agent
evaluations. So today I'm going to be
talking with a uh the main and this is
really weird.
Can't figure out is it up and down.
I can't figure out
yeah sorry about that.
So today I want to uh start with u I
have one single argument about uh AI
data readiness is that as we are
evaluating the agents we also need to
evaluate the readiness of the underlying
data layer.
So this is how it goes. Um at least in
genetic ro we uh we are mandated to
build an agenti system. We choose some
data sets and then ML engineers AI
engineers are working on it. You know a
couple of months we put some work
together uh put the framework together
and then when it comes to evals we see
it's not performing very well and then
we were wondering what happened what
went wrong. I mean we went with uh you
know we went to all the langin blogs all
the py uh blogs uh you know hopefully we
actually applied the best practices but
wasn't performing then we look into
prompt engineering we look for hope for
the better models but what we realize
later is that the agents are not
performing in vacuum right they are
working on top of a data layer and the
underlying data layer there is is
something we need to also look at. I'll
give a couple of examples and then I'll
go into a little more detail on that. Uh
think of uh think of like there was this
uh particular example where we had a
data layer uh which was oriented towards
more like you know dashboarding and
reporting and when we put a uh agent on
top of it uh what happened is that you
know it was not performing well and then
we saw that it was oriented towards data
warehousing or reporting or
dashboarding. So that is something we
need to look into.
Now uh looking into this what we are uh
we have come up with is an agent uh AI
data agency evaluations framework and
what we are calling it uh at least as of
now it's an evolving d uh framework is
there are five dimensions to it. So from
left to right uh clockwise um the first
is data quality. It's kind of obvious
right how how sound the data is
technically right in terms of
completeness consistency and freshness
then semantic and metadata we u you know
do we have metadata for that data set
for example let's say we are dealing
with a postgress uh postgress SQL
database and do we have table and column
comments or do we have a blob for
containing the context of that
access and governance uh can we access
the you know relevant data at all or the
agent can access the relevant data or
not. Structural readiness. This is where
I was giving that example of the uh data
database. Uh what we found out is that
the data m actually had a a concept of
entity attribute value and you can look
it up what it is. But the bottom line is
that that is not very conducive to uh
running agents on top of it. Then we
have also generalizability where the we
are looking into like whether the agent
the data layer has is generalizable or
can it go beyond the happy path.
So with that uh what we have done is we
have actually recently got a new rips
workshop. I know scali also has another
workshop approved. Congratulations for
that. We have a new rips workshop
approved in Paris and we're looking
forward to talking more about uh it and
uh basically what we are doing is
putting the community together who are
building data infrastructure for agenti
and we're also building who are also
building the evaluations and benchmarks
for agenti.
So you can uh look into the website you
know feel free to u scan the QR code and
then
so this is uh this was truly a
collaborative effort between within
gentech and outside um academia industry
and outside community and we're also
looking to continue this uh this
conversation in the newix workshop.
Thank you.
[applause]
Now welcoming Scott Clark, co-founder,
CEO of Distributional, how better evals
can bring abundance through accelerated
scientific discovery.
Hey
>> everybody, thank you all for sticking
around. I know it's Sunday afternoon and
this is the penultimate talk. Um, soon
as my slides come up, uh, I'll look
forward to, uh, chatting to you guys
about, uh, bringing better abundance
through better evals.
There we go.
Excellent. So, uh, as was said before,
uh, my name is Scott Clark. I'm
co-founder and CEO of Distributional,
and I'm building Taria Scientific. And
I'm going to tell you about how you get
better abundance. But first, I'm going
to define what that means. So, what does
abundance through AI mean? In my mind is
better scientific discoveries that lead
to new materials, more efficient energy.
This leads to better medicine, more
efficient uh ways of travel. It it
basically means living in a sci-fi
future.
It's less about how do we get rid of
more white collar jobs and put everybody
out of work. And it's more about how do
we improve people's quality of life. And
I believe that for the first time, we're
finally able to meaningfully accelerate
scientific discovery with AI. The last
few months have really unlocked quite a
bit of capability and this has been a
passion of mine for a long time. I've
been trying to solve this problem for
the last 20 years of my career with
varying degrees of success.
It started back when I was doing
undergrad and leading up to my PhD where
every single problem that I solved,
every single group that I worked with
from protein folding to quantum
mechanics simulation to metagenome
assembly always ended with the same
problem at the end. We'd build something
great and then we would need to tune it.
Lots of different knobs and levers,
hyperparameters, whatever you want to
call them. If you could make the graphs
and the benchmarks slightly better, you
got a better paper. We jokingly call
this grad student descent because it was
often the role of the grad students to
sit up late at night kind of tuning
knobs in a highdimensional space trying
to get that slightly better paper. Um
people did apply smart techniques to
this simulated annealing genetic
algorithms local methods. Um I fell in
love with Beijian optimization and that
became core to my PhD thesis and it
ended up being uh the central point of
my first AI startup. SIGOP started this
in 2014 and our goal was to solve the
parameter tuning problem and over the
course of seven years we worked with
great firms like Netflix tuning the
recommener systems, AMX tuning their
fraud systems, Open AI in the early days
when they were a nonprofit lab uh tuning
their early RL systems um as well as
about a trillion dollars worth of hedge
funds and several hundred academics used
our free program to tune their papers.
everything from materials design to drug
discovery. When I sold the company to
Intel in 2020, we used it to tune
everything from chip design to
benchmaxing MLF when that was what
everybody was overfitting to at the
time. So the goal was optimization at
scale for problems that really mattered
and it worked really well except when it
didn't. So the problem was it would fit
exactly what you told it to do. it would
always optimize what they gave us. But
often times when customers would come
back, they'd say, "Yeah, you made that
number go up, but some other number went
down."
And that's the problem with an
optimizer. The very best thing about a
blackbox optimizer is it will optimize
any eval you give it. And the very worst
thing about a blackbox optimizer is it
will blindly optimize any eval you give
it.
And so you could make a really accurate
fraud detection system if only 1% of
your transactions are fraud by saying
nothing's fraud. 99% accuracy right
there.
Additionally, we're still a long ways
from just setting these systems up to be
completely autonomous. I think we're a
long way away from just saying goal
solve stable confu stable fusion
containment, solve cancer, these sorts
of things. And even if the model came
back with something, how could we trust
it? And that's the other side of this
coin. You need to optimize these systems
and you need to trust them. And that's
what I set out to do with
distributional. I thought I would attack
this in the most complex mathematical
way possible. Big statistical tests and
we would we would we would solve chaos
and we'd solve non-stationerity. Uh and
this was a terrible idea because nobody
likes tests. They didn't have the data
and everybody was just yoloing models
into production anyway. So I pivoted the
company. This is what you do. You're
failing. pivot um analytics. So, let's
catch the evals that are that are
sneaking through your system. How do we
find patterns in behavior in order to be
able to say, "Hey, this is the unknown
unknown." The eval
is a really good idea, but it's more of
a feature, let alone a product, let
alone a startup. So now what I'm doing
is I'm applying everything that I've
done in the last 20 years to attack the
scientific problem of how do we
accelerate science focusing in on what
actually matters building bespoke evals
that know physics that know about the
scientific research process that know
how to do hypothesis validation so you
can spin the flywheel of a whatif
machine faster and faster and faster
doing what I did in grad school that
used to take six months in six hours
instead.
If you're interested in this, we're
building this in the open. It's going to
be open sourced at Nurips. Uh there's a
private beta right now. Follow along and
I would love to chat with you if you're
building anything computational science
related.
[applause]
All right, thank you folks for sticking
around. This is the last talk for today
with Aayush Agawal, product lead at Uber
on eval, the engine for agent
improvement.
>> Awesome. Well, uh, give a round to you
all because you're here till the end.
This is a a full day event and I'm
really proud of you all for being here.
So, just thank you for being here
towards the end. Um, I'm well aware that
I am the one who's in between you all
from being here and a beautiful Berkeley
day outside. So, let's try to warm up
the room and see who's here. Uh, so
firstly, super simple one. Uh, who took
an Uber today? Uh, quick raise of hands.
All right, we have a few. That's great.
Um, but more importantly, uh, who
actually, uh, wrote an eval for an agent
in production? Let's see who are the
real builders.
All right. Okay, cool. And now the last
one. You have to be proud of this. Uh,
did those eval tell you something that
changed the way that you shipped your
product?
All right. All right. Great. Great. So
that the difference between having eval
as a checkbox versus an eval actually
changing your product direction. That's
what we spent over a year at Uber trying
to make sure that every agent team was
able to do. And I'm going to talk to you
all about that today. So at Uber, we've
been shipping agents throughout our
ecosystem, both for external agents, so
you can book a ride through your voice
as well as internally. And the thing
that's powering all of that at
enterprise scale is our Uber agent
platform which I manage. And there's a
bunch of different components across
that to help agent teams not worry about
the infrastructure. And the thing that
I'm going to talk about today is eval
which is what this room is all focused
on which is really exciting. So one
thing that we saw across the board is
that every team wanted high quality
production agents but they started to do
one common thing. They said that, hey,
let me just ship the agent and I'll
think about eval.
And it was a very rational decision
because for them, they just wanted to go
prove product market fit. They wanted to
see if it even worked. But what that did
was that then they got caught in this
relentless loop of retrofitting evals
later and trying to figure out why did
that agent break. And so what we found
was that there were true friction points
that teams had that were preventing them
from getting to that state earlier on.
And we as a platform team decided to
make that frictionless for them. So
let's talk about those to make eval
default. So the first thing and this was
kind of mentioned across the board is
the starting is tracing. And so what we
did was we made sure that as soon as the
first development started they had
tracing at every single environment. And
what that allowed teams to do is
understand and have a foundation for
setting up the rest of their
evaluations. they could just build an
agent, vibe with it, send it out and all
of the information of how it's been
changing over time is there and not
something they have to add retrofit
retrofit. The second was that once they
were able to get insight um able to get
their data, how to get insights out of
it, teams didn't know how to start with
developing an eval. They didn't know
what was the best way to write it or
where. And so what we did was that we
had the context of how the agent was
built the the documentation around it
and we figured out what is the best
starter kit evaluators and sent those
insights directly to the builders in
Slack so that they could understand hey
uh I don't know what an LLM judges but I
do know what it means to have a tool
contradiction and make a change because
of that.
What we also saw is that eval with
agents is very different. They are not
QA tests that are purely engineering.
But we needed to bridge that gap so that
the teams that are closest to the
customer like product and customer teams
had an ability to understand those. CLI
experiences really democratized that.
And so by building skills that managed
uh the eval, we saw that teams were able
to allow their product teams to own this
entire process.
Finally, this was something that we
couldn't build a tool away for. It was
changing the narrative around what an
what an eval is meant to do. So we
changed teams narratives from hey is
your eval 90% plus to do you actually
trust your eval? What have you done and
changed about your road map because your
evals have told you that? And how
quickly have you been able to update
your data sets? Is your data set five
five months old and not really up to
date with your product?
All of this helped us ship products
faster and catch issues much earlier in
the product life cycle. So what we're
launching really soon is a rider voice
booking in Uber and what that and what
we saw with our eval was that although
we had a 95% plus offline eval when we
saw a production eval showing us that
the number of turns per session were way
higher than average. We looked into that
deeply and saw that hey there's actually
um customer that is trying to book a
ride to SFO but somebody in the
background said hey I want pizza and the
the agent took that as an in as an input
and started rerouting them to the
nearest pizza space and so we realized
that we needed to have the agent
understand true intent and have no ops
where it was not needing to be listened
to. So that was only possible because we
had evals as well as the products teams
in the loop. So this is the the
evolution we had at Uber where we had
eval the default come in because of
these interventions and now we're moving
to eval is this engine and this is where
we're really excited where traces go
into failures which are automatically
categorized and then get proposed as sol
as updates to the agent to the
evaluators and the teams are basically
accepting and rejecting that and that
improvement feedback loop is what really
helps teams bring agents that customers
really love. And so that's the
difference between having an eval metric
that's a score for something that you
know versus an engine that helps you
continuously improve agents tuned
towards what the customer cares about.
That's what makes each of your trips
magical at Uber and we're excited to
continue building this out. Thank you.
[applause]
And that concludes our sessions. We have
a reception and uh posters to see
downstairs. Thank you for your presence
and your attention. Have a great week
ahead.